♪ [music] ♪
♪ [muziek] ♪
[crowd cheering]
[drukke menigte]
*[Gil Guillory] Fighting is as old as, as human kind has ever been.*
[Gil Guillory] Vechtsport is zo oud als de mensheid ooit is geweest.
*Something about beating another man,*
Er is iets aan een andere man,
*into submission,*
tot onderwerping verslaan.
*that the world is attracted to.*
Dat de wereld tot aangetrokken is.
*What is it?*
Wat is het?
Man is the only species on earth,
De mens is de enige soort op aarde,
outside of its natural environment.
buiten zijn natuurlijke omgeving.
And what society has caused to do
En wat de samenleving veroorzaakt heeft,
is take out a couple of different things
is om een paar dingen weg te nemen
out of the equation. The first is.
uit de vergelijking. De eerste is.
The rules of man.
De regels van de mens.
The rules of man suggest that man is a warrior.
De regels van de mens geven aan dat de mens een krijger is.
*By nature he's a warrior so when you say, "Fight"!*
Van natuur is hij een krijger dus wanneer je zegt "Vecht"!
*Everyone's gonna turn and look. Everyone.*
Iedereen gaat zich omdraaien en kijken. Iedereen.
*"Fighting is truth"*
"Vechten is waarheid"
[clapping and drumming]
[klappen en drummen]
♪ [music] ♪
♪ [muziek] ♪
[crowd cheering]
[menigte juicht]
*[Gil] Very few men will actually walk the aisles.*
[Gil] Zeer weinig mannen zullen wel dergelijk de gangpaden belopen.
*And get into that combat arena*
En dat strijdgebied binnengaan
*And very few men will do it 20 to 30 times.*
En zeer weinig mannen zullen dat 20 tot 30 keer doen.
*Most of these guys have fight they'll never fight again.*
De meeste van deze mannen die gevochten hebben zullen nooit meer vechten.
*They've think they can do it, they want to do it.*
Ze denken dat ze het kunnen doen, ze willen het doen."
*They want everybody to know that they're cage fighters.*
Ze willen dat iedereen weet dat ze kooivechters zijn.
*But when that door close in, you'd hear that lock "click"!*
Maar wanneer die deur sluit, hoor je dat slot "klik"!
*And when it's time to go*
En wanneer het tijd is om te beginnen
*And that guy looks at you across the cage.*
En die andere man kijkt naar jou van de andere kant van de kooi.
*And you can't give him the same look that he gave you.*...
En je kan hem niet dezelfde .. blik werpen die hij jou wierp.
*Now you know you're in trouble.*
Weet je nu dat je in de problemen zit.
*Every fight has a story thats yet to be played out.*
Elke vechtpartij heeft een verhaal die nog moet worden uitgespeeld.
*As a match maker, I have to imagine that story.*
Als een wedstrijd maker, moet ik me dat verhaal inbeelden.
*I have to write the script of that story.*
Ik moet het script van dat verhaal schrijven.
*What would happen?*
Wat zou er gebeuren?
*If you were in your tribe, I was in my tribe *
Als je in je stam was en ik was in mijn stam
*And we came across each other. What would happen?*
En we botsten tegen elkaar op. Wat zou er gebeuren?
*Beside bashing each other in the head with a rock.*
Naast elkaar met een steen op het hoofd slaan.
*Let's throw it outta there*
Laten we het er uit gooien
*This is what "Combat" is*
Dat is wat "Strijd" is
*It's not two men standing up. *
Het is niet twee mannen die opstaan
*And just punching each other in the head and stomach.*
En gewoon elkaar op het hoofd en in de buik slaan.
*Combat encompasses everything.*
Strijd omvat alles.
*Do what you can to win a fight.*
Doe wat je kan om een gevecht te winnen.
[crowd yelling]
[menigte roept]
[thud, thud, thud]
[plof, plof, plof]
[horn blowing]
[hoorn blaast]
[crowd cheering and clapping]
[menigte juicht en klapt]
*We're bringing back the pure essence of combat.*
Wij brengen de pure essentie van strijd terug.
♪ [music] ♪
♪ [muziek] ♪
[crowd cheering and clapping]
[menigte juicht en klapt]
*I can take any man. And I'll make him a star.*
Ik kan eender welke man nemen en ik maak hem een ster.
- [*DUSTIN POIRIER*] *My dream is to be...*
- [DUSTIN POIRIER] Mijn droom is om...
*The best fighter.* *At a 155 lbs in the world*
de beste vechter te zijn van 70 kg in de wereld.
Fighting is what I do.
Vechten is wat ik doe.
My father was a fighter.
Mijn vader was een vechter.
My grandfather was a fighter.
Mijn grootvader was een vechter.
It's just in my blood.
Het zit gewoon in mijn bloed.
[punching]
[ponsen]
What we're doing on this local level is,
Wat we doen op dit lokaal niveau is,
We take these young guys, We're developing them.
we nemen deze jonge kerels, we ontwikkelen ze.
So that they can gradually progress,
Zodat ze gelijdelijk aan kunnen evolueren,
To the big leagues.
naar de grote competities.
So, we are. In essence,
Dus, we zijn in wezen,
a minor league mixed martial arts.
een kleine competitie gemixte vechtsport.
We're a feeder to UFC, Strike force, DREAM.
Wij zijn een voeder voor UFC, Strike Force, DREAM.
But they won't get to the big time.
Maar ze zullen niet bij de grote termijn geraken
If we don't have these shows.
Als we deze shows niet houden.
We have to have these shows.
We moeten deze shows houden.
Fans have to support us.
Fans moeten ons supporteren.
In order to get our local guys to the next level.
Om onze lokale kerels naar het volgende niveau te krijgen,
Those with talent.
diegene met talent.
- When I first started fighting,
- Toen ik eerst begon te vechten,
The sport of fighting.
de vechtsport,
I didn't even expect to, I had no, not one thought of money.
Had ik niet eens verwacht, ik had geen, geen enkel gedachte aan geld.
Or fame or anything like that on my mind.
Of roem of iets dergelijks aan mijn gedachten.
And I just wanted to fight, that's it, Simple and plain.
En ik wou gewoon vechten, dat is alles, eenvoudig en ronduit.
I called the place. And I ask them.
Ik belde die plaats. En ik vroeg hen
So I said, If come over here and train, Will I be able to fight?
dus...als ik naar daar ga en train, zal ik echt kunnen vechten?
Really, against other opponents?
Tegen andere tegenstanders?
And they said "Yeah, you will"
En ze zeiden "Ja, je zal dat kunnen."
I was there the next day.
De volgende dag stond ik daar.
[train honking]
[trein toetert]
[thud,thud,thud]
[plof, plof, plof]
♪ [music] ♪
♪ [muziek] ♪
- [Tim] *Defend! Defend! *
- [Tim] Verdedig! Verdedig!
- * I'm stuck.*
- Ik zit vast.
* I know, come the other way! Come this way, come to me!*
- Dat weet ik, kom langs de andere kant! Kom naar deze kant, kom naar mij!
Defend! *Don't get knocked out right here.*
Verdedig! Laat je niet hier knock-out geslagen worden.
*There you go...*
Daar ga je...
* Feet on the wall, push away.*
Voeten op de muur, duw weg.
*Flip! Flip! Flip!*
Draai! Draai! Draai!
♪ [music] ♪
♪ [muziek] ♪
*[alarm ringing]*
[alarm rinkelt]
- *Stop. It's not your skill, its not yours.*
- Stop. Het is niet je vaardigheid, het is niet van jou.
- *There's a music playing, this is Tim*
- Er speelt muziek, dit is Tim.
-["Crazy" Tim Credeur] What we're doing today with MMA,
- ["Crazy" Tim Credeur] Wat we vandaag doen met MMA,
and with mixed martial arts.
en met de gemixte vechtsport
Is what martial arts was always suppose to be.
Is wat de vechtsport altijd al moest zijn,
And the revitalization of martial arts in America is starting to happen.
En de revitalisering van de vechtsport in Amerika begint.
The reality of martial arts through MMA
De realiteit van de vechtsport door MMA
Has been boiled down to, whats true and whats just crazy.
Werd ingekookt tot, wat is waar en wat is gewoon gek.
What's crazy movie stuff.
Wat is gekke filmstof.
*There's no 7 year old black belts over here. That's not real.*
Er zijn hier geen 7-jarige zwarte gordels. Dat is niet echt.
*We don't have 5 year olds doing flying jump kicks, through the walls.*
Wij hebben geen 5-jarigen die vliegende sprongschoppen door de muren doen.
That's just not the reality of it.
Dat is gewoon niet de realiteit ervan.
[swoosh, swoosh]
[zwiep, zwiep]
These guys who've done these traditional martial arts,
Deze kerels die deze traditionele vechtsporten gedaan hebben,
In these traditional martial arts school
In traditionele vechtsport scholen,
They can't win a fight in an MMA match.
kunnen geen gevecht in een MMA wedstrijd winnen.
How can that be possible?
Hoe is dat mogelijk?
If you spent 20 years in a martial arts academy.
Als je 20 jaar in een vechtsport academie besteed hebt
*You've been doing kata's and breaking fake boards.*
Deed je kata's en het breken van valse borden.
*And wearing funny belts.*
En droeg je grappige gordels.
*You haven't been training to be a fighter.*
Je trainde niet om een vechter te worden.
*You've been training to go be in bar and belly circus.*
Je trainde om in een bar en Bailey circus te gaan.
That's not martial arts,
Dat is geen vechtsport,
That's crazy talk, that's ridiculous.
dat is gekke praat, dat is belachelijk.
When martial arts was developed for samurais and for the warriors
Toen vechtsport werd ontwikkeld voor samoerais en voor de krijgers,
of the warrior caste in Asia,
van de krijger kaste in Azië,
you know, people fell off.
je weet wel, mensen vielen af.
And those people that did not get to become samurais.
En die mensen mochten geen samoerai worden,
They did not get to become warriors.
Ze mochten geen krijgers worden.
Those people got to become farmers.
Die mensen werden landbouwers.
To make it for everyone, like I've said before,
Om het voor iedereen te maken, zoals ik al zei,
is to make it not what it really is.
Is om het te maken wat het niet echt is.
[thud, thud, thud]
[plof, plof, plof]
- *[male voice] Don't leave any blood splattered on that sink.*
- [mannelijke stem] Laat geen bloed spetters na op de wastafel,
*Or on the tank. Go wash yourself off.*
Of op de tank. Ga je wassen,
*And then wash your area off too, okay?*
En dan was je gebied ook, ok?
Okay? That's like a health violation, ok
Ok? Dat is net een gezondheidsovertreding, ok.
- *[Tim] Okay guys, look too, that's a good point.*
- [Tim] Ok jongens, kijk ook, dat is een goed punt.
Health inspector came and there was some blood,
De gezondheid inspecteur kwam en er was wat bloed
and he was pissed you know, he didn't say much..
en hij was kwaad weet je, hij zei niet veel...
But if you bleed or somethin' like that, make sure you clean your stuff up.
Maar als je bloedt of iets zoiets, wees er dan zeker van dat je je stof schoonmaakt.
Don't leave blood all over the place, it just make us look ridiculous.
Laat niet overal bloed achter, het laat ons belachelijk lijken.
We're suppose to be a martial arts school.
Wij moeten een vechtsport school voorstellen.
Help me, Help you
Help mij, help jou
♪ [music] ♪
♪ [muziek] ♪
- *[Gil] You know I grew up, watching men who work hard.*
- [Gil] Weet je ik groeide op, kijkend naar mannen die hard werkten.
*Who party hard and on a Friday or Saturday night.*
Die hard feesten en op een vrijdag- of zaterdagavond,
They weren't scared to fight hard.
Waren ze niet bang om hard te vechten.
*What we're trying to do at USA-MMA is to bring back the feel,*
Wat we proberen te doen bij USA-MMA is om het gevoel
*and the excitement of a live event.*
en de opwinding van een live evenement terug te brengen.
*And we do them in rodeo arenas and civic centers,*
En we doen die in rodeo pistes en stadscentrums,
*across South Louisiana.*
dwars door Zuid-Louisiana.
*And it's just me, my wife and the kids.*
En het is alleen ik, mijn vrouw en de kinderen.
- *[Gil's Wife] There's a definitely a misperception about the sport*
- [Gil's Vrouw] Er is zeker en vast een misvatting over de sport.
*They laugh at the sport. They can't wait to say,*
Ze lachen met de sport. Ze kunnen niet... wachten om te zeggen
"Oh, really? Well, that's human cock fighting."
"Oh echt? Wel, dat is menselijk haan vechten."
I've heard that so many times and it's aggravating because what?
Ik heb het al zoveel keer gehoord en het is ergelijk waarom?
*John McCain* said that 10-15 years ago, 'human cock fighting"
John McCain zei dat zo'n 10-15 jaar geleden 'menselijk haan vechten'.
*And actually it probably was back then.*
En dat was het toen waarschijnlijk ook.
*You know you can be in any weight class.*
Weet je je kon in eender welke klasse zitten.
*There was no rules at all*
Er waren helemaal geen regels.
But the way that the sports developed since then.
Maar de manier waarop... de sport ontwikkeld is sinds toen.
You know it's very... one of the safest sports around.
Weet je het is echt... een van de veiligste sporten die er bestaan.
*Rodeo's, people die you know. all the time, in rodeos*
Rodeo's, weet je mensen sterven de hele tijd, in rodeo's.
*They die in NASCAR. All the time*
Ze sterven in NASCAR. De hele tijd.
*But because this is a new sport people don't know what it is*
Maar omdat dit een nieuwe sport is mensen weten niet wat het is
*And they see so much blood, they don't understand.*
En ze zien zoveel bloed, ze begrijpen niet dat
Blood is superficial. These guys has four ounce gloves on.
Bloed oppervlakkig is. Deze kerels dragen 110 gram handschoenen.
*They don't have 16 ounce gloves on.* [Thud!]
Ze dragen geen 450 gram  [Plof!] handschoenen.
*So there's no brain damage.*
Dus er is geen hersenbeschadiging.
*They're getting punched with a 4 ounce glove.*
Ze worden geponst met een 110 gram handschoen.
*If a guy in the ring is hurt, the referee will stop the fight.*
Als een kerel in de ring gewond is, zal de scheidsrechter het gevecht stoppen.
*That won't happen in boxing.*
Dat gebeurt niet met boksen.
*His heirarchy has to be on the ground he can even be hurt.*
Zijn hiërarchie moet op de grond liggen, hij kan zelfs gewond zijn.
*So as long as he can stand himself up* *He could continue to fight.*
Zolang hij zelf kan opstaan, kan hij verder vechten.
*And that doesn't happen in MMA either.*
En dat gebeurt ook niet in MMA.
*I knew when I started dating him that he was a former boxer.*
Ik wist toen ik met hem begon uit te gaan dat hij een voormalige bokser was.
*That he wrestled also, Pro, which I thought was insane.*
En dat hij ook worstelde, Pro, waarvan ik dacht dat dat echt gek was.
[audience chanting] Let's go Gil! Uh! Uh!
[toeschouwers zingen] Let's go Gil! Oh! Oh!
[slamming]
[slaan]
Uh! Uh!
Oh! Oh!
- [Gil's Wife] It's in his blood. I mean my son's 5.
- [Gil's Vrouw] Het zit in zijn bloed. Ik bedoel mijn zoon is nu 5.
*And you know he's gonna fight one day.*
En je weet dat hij op een dag gaat vechten.
*You know, as safe as it is, you still don't wanna see your son *
Weet je, zelfs al is het zo veilig, je wil toch nog altijd niet
*even fall off his bike. You know. *
je zoon zelfs van zijn fiets zien vallen. Weet je wel.
And he's gonna fight one day. I will not be able to stop him.
En op een zal hij vechten. Ik zal niet in staat zijn om hem te stoppen.
It's in his blood.
Het zit in zijn bloed.
My husband, when we argue he goes to the gym and spars.
Mijn man, wanneer we ruzie hebben gaat hij naar de gym en spart.
*And comes back much better, much better.*
En hij komt veel, veel beter terug.
There's a lot of skill involved.
Er is veel vaardigheid in betrokken.
It's not just some, you know, bar fight.
Het is niet gewoon, je weet wel, een bar gevecht.
If the guys calls all the time
Als de kerels de hele tijd bellen
"I wanna fight" , "I wanna fight" "I wanna fight"
"Ik wil vechten", "Ik wil vechten", "Ik wil vechten"
Well, if you're not trained. You know we can't put you in there.
Wel, als je niet getraind bent. Weet je dat we je daar niet in kunnen steken.
It's not safe.
Het is niet veilig.
- *[Gil] Yeah this is a rodeo arena But you still not gonna fight on my show.*
- [Gil] Ja dit is een rodeo piste maar je kan nog niet in mijn show vechten.
A lot of these kids that call me up.
Veel van deze kinderen die me opbellen
Wanting to fight, think they first have the ability.
Die willen vechten, denken dat ze de vaardigheid hebben.
Then they think it's just, it's easy. Let's go and do it
Dan denken ze dat het gewoon, makkelijk is. Laten we het doen.
So, I as a 38,39 year old man
Dus, ik als een 38,39-jarige man,
The first thing I do is go to the gym and I'll spar 'em.
Het eerste wat ik doe is naar de gym gaan en met hen sparren.
[swoosh] [ thud, thud]
[zwiep] [plof, plof]
Five guys walking off the street, I'm looking for one thing,
Vijf kerels wandelend van de straat, ik kijk voor een ding,
all of them wanna be world champion.
ze willen allemaal wereldkampioen worden.
But the most important thing is, Dedication
Maar het meest belangrijke is, Toewijding
[thud, thud, thud]
[plof, plof, plof]
[timer ringing]
[timer rinkelt]
-*[Tim] Don't commit to run.*
-[Tim] Denk niet van uit te voeren.
*Commit to the exchange. You're committing to not getting hurt.*
Denk aan de uitwisseling. Je hecht jezelf aan niet gewond te geraken.
- *[Albert Stainback] Actually, quite afraid of being hit when I'm in the gym.*
- [Albert Stainback] Eigenlijk ben ik bang om geraakt te worden in de gym.
*It sucks! You know you feel it.*
Het zuigt! Je voelt dat.
*But when I'm fighting, I just wanna hit 'em and it just happens.*
Maar wanneer ik aan het vechten ben, wil ik ze gewoon raken en het gebeurt.
*And I hit them. And they fall unconscious and I feel good.*
En ik raak ze. En ze vallen bewusteloos en ik voel me goed.
*The energy in the cage makes the whole thing feel spiritual for me.*
De energie in de kooi maakt het hele ding geestelijk voor me voelen.
Like another world
Net een andere wereld.
It's almost like the universe is this big machine.
Het is bijna alsof het heelal een grote machine is.
And I am, you know, I'm operating it.
And ik, weet je wel, ik bedien die.
I don't believe in God.
Ik geloof niet in God.
I don't believe in destiny.
Ik geloof niet in lot.
I don't believe in predetermination or whatever anything like that.
I geloof niet in voorbestemming of zoiets dergelijks.
But I will say I am dazzled by the way I look at my life,
Maar ik ga zeggen dat ik verblind ben door de manier waarop ik naar mijn leven kijk,
the way it's turned out and the way it's just like interconnected with fighting
de manier waarop het teweeg kwam en de manier waarop het gewoon verbonden is
the way I feel it is.
met vechten, de manier waarop ik het voel.
It's the only thing that I really think I'm good at, if anything.
Het is het enige waarvan ik denk dat ik goed in ben.
You know if you could say I'm good at anything, it would be that.
Weet je als je kon zeggen dat ik ergens goed in ben, dat zou het zijn.
- *[Gil] Guy's got a lot of talent.*
- [Gil] Deze kerel heeft veel talent.
*He's not a bad looking kid. *
Hij is geen slecht uitziende jongen.
*But I see potential in him outside of fighting.*
Maar zie ik in hem potentieel buiten vechten.
*I think that if he really put himself to anything.*
Ik denk dat als hij zich echt in iets inzet,
*He can do anything, he wanted to do.*
Hij alles kan doen wat hij ook maar wilde doen.
- [Albert] I kinda wanted to be my only option.
- [Albert] Ik wilde dat het eigenlijk mijn enige optie was.
Cause I love it that much.
Omdat ik het zo graag doe.
Maybe that's a little fool hearted, but I don't care.
Misschien is het een beetje te bedot, maar dat kan me niet schelen.
- [Gil] Many mistakes that a young fighter are making.
- [Gil] Veel fouten die jonge vechters maken,
I guess, the most important one.
Ik denk dat de meest belangrijke,
Is that they're forgetting. That there's life after fighting.
Is dat ze vergeten dat er leven is naast vechten.
Pursuing that MMA dream.
Hun MMA droom nastreven,
You know I can't fault anybody for that.
Weet je ik kan niemand daarvoor beschuldigen.
Because I pursued my own dream. But I did work at the same time.
Want ik streefde mijn eigen droom na. Maar ik werkte tegelijkertijd.
I went to college at the same time.
Ik ging tegelijkertijd naar college.
You don't understood the sheer dynamics of it.
Je begrijpt de pure dynamiek er niet van.
Most fighters 99% of fighters end up broken and destitute.
Meeste vechters, 99% van vechters breken uiteindelijk en zijn verstoken.
That's just the truth of it.
Dat is gewoon de waarheid ervan.
They might make a little bit of money here and there.
Misschien krijgen ze hier en daar wat geld.
But most fighters, most people climbing into the ring or the cage
Maar de meeste vechters, de meeste mensendie in de kooi of ring klimmen
don't make a penny.
verdienen geen cent.
*- [Tim] You try to help them the best you can*
- [Tim] Je probeert ze zo goed mogelijk te helpen
But they're not my children. So what can I do?
Maar ze zijn mijn kinderen niet. Dus wat kan ik doen?
- [Gil] Give them advice, that's about it.
- [Gil] Geef ze advies, dat is alles.
Keep going with USA - MMA and [laughs]
Ga door met USA - MMA en [lacht]
Be the best company, nobody's ever heard of.
Wees het beste bedrijf, niemand ooit van over heeft gehoord.
[cheering and clapping]
[juichen en klappen]
*- [Gil] Hello and welcome to this weeks edition*
- [Gil] Welkom bij deze week's editie,
*of the Combat Sports Report. My name is Gil "The Thrill" Guillorey.*
Van de strijd sport support. Mijn naam is Gil "The Thrill" Gillorey.
What we have tonight is "Natural Disaster III."
Wat we vanavond hebben is "Natural Disaster III."
August 1st, Tonight. SugArena.
1 Augustus, vanavond. Sugarena,
*It's gonna happen tonight guys. We have 14 bouts.*
Het zal vanavond gebeuren mensen. We hebben 14 wedstrijden.
*A little too many fights*
Een beetje te veel vechten.
*Our main event tonight is "Joe Torres versus Dustin Poirier*
Ons belangrijkste evenement vanavond is "Joe Torres versus Dustin Poirier
*Please, come out! Support these guys.*
Gelieve te komen! Supporter voor deze kerels.
*Support your local fighter.*
Steun uw lokale vechter.
*We have, Mike Jackson against Albert Stainback.*
We hebben, Mike Jackson tegen Albert Stainback.
*He's from Gladiator, Lafayette.*
Hij is van Gladiator, Lafayette.
- [Albert Stainback] I think a stare down. Is something very important for a fight.
- [Albert Stainback] Ik denk dat neerstaren belangrijk is in een gevecht.
And yes I do practice in the mirror
En ja ik oefen dat voor de spiegel.
I'll sit in the mirror in the bathroom and just be like. [deep breathing]
Ik zit dan voor de spiegel in de badkamer en ik ben gewoon zo van [diepe ademhaling]
If you're staring them down
Als je ze neerstaart
And you see that certain look
En je ziet die bepaalde blik
I believed that you know, you're already in their head.
Geloof ik weet je wel, dat je al in hun hoofd zit.
And that, and that helps. You know.
En dat helpt, Weet je wel.
But then you get those people, and this is when you know
Maar dan zijn er ook van die mensen en dat is wanneer je weet
It's gonna be a fight.
Dat het een gevecht zal zijn.
When they just look right back at you dude...
Wanneer ze zo recht terug naar je kijken...
And it's a.. I like those even better actually.
En het is een...Ik heb die eigenlijk wel liever.
I like it when they grind, you know, right back.
Ik heb het graag wanneer ze recht terug malen.
When they are not scared.
Wanneer ze niet bang zijn.
When they do not back down. I love it!
Wanner ze zich niet terugtrekken. Ik hou daarvan!
- [Dustin Poirier] People feel the same way when they get in the cage.
- [Dustin Poirier] Mensen voelen hetzelfde wanneer ze de kooi binnengaan.
But other people in the outside don't really notice it how,
Maar de anderen buiten de kooi kunnen niet zien hoe,
you know, unless they do it, how peaceful it really is inside there.
weet je wel, tenzij ze het zelf doen, hoe vreedzaam het binnen echt is.
It's crazy, so pure.
Het is gek, zo puur.
- [Albert] When Dustin's in there he looks like a serial killer.
- [Albert] Wanneer Dustin daar binnen is ziet hij er uit als een seriemoordenaar.
You know and I feel like the same, about myself.
En ik voel net hetzelfde, over mezelf.
Are we done yet?
Zijn we bijna klaar?
*[announcer] Judges in the back park*
[omroeper] Jury's in het achter park
*will be meeting at 7 o'clock. All fighters...*
zullen om 7 uur ontmoeten. Alle vechters...
- [Alvin Tapmam] *I wanna go over a few things with you first, again,*
- [Alvin Tapmam] Ik wil eerst weer met je over een paar dingen gaan,
*I met most of you earlier, *
Ik onmoette de meeste onder jullie al,
*my name is Alvin Tapmam,*
mijn naam is Alvin Tapmam,
*I'm the commissioner, For Athletics in State of Louisiana.*
Ik ben de commissaris, voor Athletisme in de Staat Louisiana.
The reason we're here primarily, the rules are followed
De reden dat we hier allereerst voor zijn, is dat de regels worden gevolgd
and safety, safety,safety is followed.
en veiligheid, veiligheid, veiligheid wordt gevolgd.
There's a lot of amateur fights on this card tonight.
Er zijn veel amateur gevechten op deze kaart vanavond.
We'll stop the fight before it gets to trouble
We zullen het gevecht stoppen voordat het voor problem zorgt.
I'm just telling you right up, fellas. I don't want anybody getting hurt.
Ik zeg het u rechuit, mensen, ik wil dat niemand gewond raakt.
We all know that when we come in here that anybody.
We weten allemaal dat wanneer we hier komen dat iedereen,
Anybody. Anybody can get severely injured in this sport.
Iedereen. Iedereen kan serieus gewond raken in deze sport.
It's happened before. I'm sure it's gonna happen again.
Het gebeurde al. Ik ben er zeker van dat het nog zal gebeuren.
You take that chance when you go in that ring.
Je neemt dat risico wanneer je die ring binnengaat.
[♪ music ♪]
♪ [muziek] ♪
- *[Gil] We're not about sellin' fight, We're selling entertainment.*
- [Gil] Bij ons gaat het niet om gevecht te verkopen, maar om vermaak te verkopen.
*And in that regard, that is our bread circuit.*
En in dat opzicht, dat is ons brood circuit.
[♪ music ♪]
♪ [muziek] ♪
- [Albert] I want people to remember me.
- [Albert] Ik wil dat mensen me herinneren.
I happen to think that we came from monkeys,
Ik geloof toevallig dat we van apen afstammen,
so my little tribute to us, getting in touch with our inner monkey
dus mijn kleine tribuut aan ons, in contact komen met onze inner-aap
is I'll get out there and I'll beat my chest twice.
is om daar buiten te gaan en ik ga mijn borst twee keer slaan.
You'll always see me do that before a fight.
Je kan me dat altijd zien doen voor een gevecht.
To me it's like that primal fight or flight thing.
Voor mij is het net dat oerstrijd of vluchtding.
*[crowd cheering and whistling]*
[menigte juicht en fluit]
In a sense I do feel like a monkey when I'm fighting.
In zekere zin voel ik me net een aap wanneer ik aan het vechten ben.
It doesn't matter what his story is.
Het doet er niet toe wat zijn verhaal is.
It doesn't matter what my story is.
Het doet er niet toe wat mijn verhaal is.
It's a matter of "Who's best fit to survive."
Het gaat er om van "Wie past het best om te overleven."
[Referee] Fight!
[Scheidsrechter] Vecht!
[crash]
[val]
[Albert Stainback] There is no feeling sorry for your opponent.*
[Albert Stainback] Er is geen medelijden voor je tegenstander.
Because you know, it's do or die.
Want weet je, het is doen of sterven.
It's either you lose or he loses.
Of jij verliest of hij verliest.
And I don't care what your story is, man.
En het kan me niet schelen wat je verhaal is, man.
I gotta look out for me and mine.
Ik moet uitkijken voor mezelf en de mijne.
[thud, thud,crash]
[plof, plof, val]
[crowd cheering]
[menigte juicht]
With victory comes this elation and that, you know, feels beautiful.
Met overwinning komt deze opgetogenheid en die, weet je, goed voelt.
Like something I have that no one can take from me.
Net alsof ik iets heb dat niemand van me af kan nemen.
You can earn, you can have a house, you can have money.
Je kan verdienen, een huis hebben, je kan geld hebben.
You can have that but you will lose that eventually.
Je kan dat wel hebben maar uiteindelijk zal je dat verliezen.
And even if you don't, what does it really mean?
En zelfs al verlies je het niet, wat betekent dat eigenlijk?
*[crowd cheering]*
[menigte juicht]
- [Dustin] Before a fight, I actually pray that nobody gets hurt you know.
- [Dustin] Voor een gevecht, bid ik eigenlijk dat niemand gewond raakt.
I don't wanna hurt him. Or I don't wanna get hurt.
Ik wil hem niet kwetsen. Of ik wil niet gekwetst worden.
But I'm not scared to lose or scared to get hurt in a fight.
Maar ik ben niet bang om te verlizen of bang om gekwetst te worden in een gevecht.
*I expect to get hit you know.*
Ik verwacht om geraakt te worden weet je.
*I know, I'm not gonna go in there and not get hit. It's a fight*
Ik weet dat ik daar niet ga binnengaan zonder geraakt worden. 't Is een gevecht,
Just like a, just like Going to work in an office
Net zoals gaan werken in een kantoor.
And not touchin' paper or somethin' you know.
En geen papier aanraken of zo weet je.
You gonna get hit it's part of the job.
Je zult geraakt worden, dat is een deel van de job.
- *[announcer] In the red pew. Dustin Poirier!*
- [omroeper] In de rode stoel. Dustin Poirier!
[crowd cheering]
[menigte juicht]
- [Tim] Dustin is similar to me.
- [Tim] Dustin is gelijk aan mij.
*He's a finisher.*
Hij is een afwerker.
*Finishers are people who don't fight to win rounds.*
Afwerkers zijn mensen die niet vechten om ronden te winnen,
*Or fight to win points, without finishing the opponent.*
Of vechten om punten te winnen, zonder de tegenstander te eindigen.
*No matter what the case. *
Maakt niet uit wat het geval is.
*Finish them, finish them, finish them!*
Eindig ze, eindig ze, eindig ze!
*Finish the opponent. Be fierce and be dominant.*
Eindig de tegenstander, wees fel en dominant.
- [male voice screaming] Round 2!
- [mannelijke stem roept] 2e Ronde!
*[crowd cheering]*
[menigte juicht]
- *[announcer] Gladiators dominate, Dustin Porier!*
- [omroeper] Gladiatoren domineren, Dustin Poirier!
- *[Tim] A lot of times, you have guys that work really really hard.*
- [Tim] Vele keren heb je kerels die echt heel hard werken.
*And make all the sacrifices.*
En die alles opofferen.
And then you have guys that have really great talents.
En dan heb je de kerels die echt goede talenten hebben.
Guys that do both. Become, you know,
Kerels die beide doen. Die, weet je,
some of the greatest fighters. The world has ever seen.
enkele van de beste vechters worden die de wereld ooit heeft gezien.
And, you know, it's exciting seeing a kid like Dustin,
En, weet je, het is opwindend om een jongen zoals Dustin te zien,
*who may be one of those guys.*
die misschien een van die kerels zal zijn.
*You know, as a coach, as a trainer, as a fighter,*
Weet je, als een coach, als een trainer, als een vechter,
*you may run into one or two of those in your life.*
loop je misschien een of twee zulke tegen het lijf in je leven.
The biggest challenge now, when it comes to a kid like Dustin,
De grootste uitdaging nu, wanneer het op een jongen zoals Dustin neerkomt,
is, you know finding somebody's not gonna kill in a couple of minutes.
is, om iemand te vinden die hij niet gaat afslachten binnen een paar minuten.
- [Gil] Will he make it to the UFC? Will he be world champion?
- [Gil] Zal hij het UFC maken? Zal hij wereldkampioen worden?
Yeah... Potential. But potential has a time frame.
Ja...potentieel. Maar potentieel heeft een tijdsbestek.
*Potential has a time limit on it.*
Potentieel heeft een tijd limiet.
*Twenty year old kid can have potential.*
Een twinig-jarige jongen kan potentieel tonen.
*But if you still, if you're 38 and somebody says*
Maar als je 38 bent en iemand zegt
*"You still have potential,"*
"Je hebt nog altijd potentieel,"
it's time to move on, you know?
dan is het tijd om verder te gaan, weet je?
So, I give Tim's gym. Probably, the nod as far as overall talent.
Dus, ik geef Tim's gym waarschijnlijk de knik voor zover het totale talent.
Cause the kids there can fight. They can fight
Want die jongens kunnen vechten Ze kunnen vechten,
*But that doesn't mean anything. On the national scale*
Maar dat betekent niets. Op nationale schaal.
♪ [music] ♪
♪ [muziek] ♪
*- [Jere Folley Chaisson] I have given my boys, freedom to express themselves.*
- [Jere Folley Chaisson] Ik heb m'n jongens de vrijheid gegeven om
*And to feel what they feel and to do what they do.*
Zichzelf uit te drukken en om te voelen wat ze voelen en om te doen wat ze doen.
He loved to fight.
Hij hield van vechten.
Not necessarily with, with someone that he wasn't get along with.
Niet noodzakelijk met iemand waar hij niet mee opschiette.
He just wanted to have a fight with somebody.
Hij wou gewoon een gevecht met iemand hebben.
One day. When he must have been just like 10 years old,
Op een dag. Toen hij misschien net 10 jaar was.
He got into trouble at school. He had a note.
Zat hij in de problemen op school Hij had een nota.
He came. He got off the school bus. And he ran in the house.
Hij kwam. Hij stapte van de schoolbus. En hij loopte het huis binnen.
He said "Here's the note. I did something at school."
Hij zei "Hier is de nota. Ik deed iets op school."
"Give me a whipping, if you're gonna give me a whipping."
"Sla me, als je me gaat slaan."
"Because I think. Somebody's ready to fight me down the road."
"Want ik denk dat iemand klaar is om me te vechten op straat."
They'd get these boxing matches going on in the neighborhood.
Ze hielden boksing wedstrijden in de buurt.
And Dustin did that, you know? And he, you know he was the best
En Dustin deed dat, weet je? En hij was de beste
out of all the little kids, the little guys that boxed.
van al de kleine kinderen, de kleine jongens die boksten.
Then there was this one guy that came to meet him at his gradma's
En toen was er die ene kerel die hem ontmoette bij zijn grootmoeder's
and said, "Well you haven't boxed me yet."
en die zei, "Wel, je hebt mij nog niet gebokst."
And Dustin, like, knocked out his teeth and broke his jaw.
En Dustin, klopte zijn tanden uit en brak zijn kaak.
And he was like 5 years \older than Dustin.
En hij was ongeveer 5 jaar ouder dan Dustin.
And we have to go to court for that. Yup!
En we moesten daarvoor naar de rechtbank gaan. Yup!
He had a respect for the law but he didn't mind
Hij respecteerde de wet maar hij vond het niet erg om
having a run in with the law.
een aanloop met de wet te hebben.
*That's when he started skipping school.*
Dat was toen hij begon te spijbelen.
*And ended up in juvenile courts and boot camp.*
En kwam terecht in jeugdrechtbanken en legerkamp
*And juvenile jail and all of that stuff.*
En jeugdgevangenis en zo van die dingen,
[clicking]
[klikken]
-[Dustin] I definitely think fighting has open the path to redemption for me.
-[Dustin] Ik denk echt dat vechten het pad naar aflossing voor mij geopend heeft.
I mean I've tried--I've been in boot camp.
Ik bedoel ik probeerde--Ik ging naar legerkamp
And juvenile detention, and programs and all these stuff.
En jeugdgevangenis en programma's en zo.
They're suppose to help you.
Die worden verondersteld om u te helpen.
And I mean, that didn't help, you know.
En ik bedoel, die helpten niet, weet je.
But when I found something that I wanted.
Maar toen ik iets vond dat ik wilde
And I really was gonna chase no matter what road block was I front of me,
En dat ik echt wou achtergaan ongeacht welke wegversperring voor me lag,
I would break it down and go get it.
Ik zou het doorbreken en er voor gaan.
This is a picture of me, right when I started training.
Dit is een foto van mij, net na ik begon te trainen.
I was probably about 200 pounds in that picture.
Ik was waarschijnlijk zo'n 90 kg op deze foto.
Big transformation. Look way different man.
Grote transformatie. Ik zag er zo anders uit man.
People I did, haven't seen me since I look like that.
Mensen die me niet zagen sinds toen ik er zo uit zag.
The're like, don't even notice me sometimes.
Ze zijn zo van, ze merken me soms niet eens.
- He's finally found, what he's been looking for all of this time.
- Hij vond eindelijk, wat hij al die tijd aan het zoeken was.
*I know that he has been waiting his whole life.*
Ik weet dat hij zijn hele leven aan het wachten was,
*To climb up somethin' and put his hands in the air.*
Om op iets te klimmen en zijn handen in de lucht te steken.
*Because he did it the best.*
Want hij deed het als de beste.
- [Tim] As a kid in America. We don't learn about honor.
- [Tim] Als een kind in Amerika, leren we niet over eer
And integrity and dignity and compassion.
En integriteit en waardigheid en compassie.
These lessons weren't taught to me. I learned math.
Deze lessen waren niet aan mij aangeleerd. Ik leerde wiskunde.
*You know I learned science. How to diagram a predicate*
Weet je ik leerde wetenschap. Hoe een schema predikaat te maken.
*But I didn't know what honor was.*
Maar ik wist niet was eer was.
*Martial arts is to develop the person.*
Vechtsport is om de persoon te ontwikkelen.
Your body, your mind and your spirit.
Uw lichaam, uw geest en uw ziel.
Everything is encompassed in that.
Alles wordt in dat omvat.
But an individual expression of that art,
Maar een individuele expressie van die kunst,
is just that it's individualistic.
is gewoon dat het individualistisch is.
How I express my Jiu-Jitsu is different from how Erin expresses his.
Hoe ik mijn Jiu-Jitsu uit is anders dan hoe Erin de zijne uit.
Or Heath expresses his.
Of hoe Heath de zijne uit.
And sometimes, some of that is gonna have to do,
En soms heeft een beetje van dat
with your background a little bit.
met uw achtergrond te maken.
You know, how athletic you are. How athletic you're not.
Weet je wel, hoe atletisch je bent. Hoe atletisch je niet bent.
Stop using muscles. Don't have any muscles really to use.
Stop met spieren te gebruiken. Je hebt geen spieren om te gebruiken.
Now, don't use any pressure or any muscle.
Nu, gebruik geen druk of geen spier.
I don't want you to do anything.
Ik wil dat je niets doet.
I just want you to grab his knee.
Ik wil gewoon dat je zijn knie vastneemt.
Now, unlock your hips, unlock. There we go.. Good!
Nu, ontsluit je heupen, ontsluit. Daar gaan we...goed!
Now, this elbow needs to come all the way down to the floor.
Nu, deze elleboog moet helemaal naar beneden op de vloer gaan.
When you get tired.
Wanner je moe wordt,
Does strength work? - *Don't have anymore*
Werkt kracht? - Ik heb geen meer.
Does technique work?
Werkt techniek?
Only way that can happen is if you technically beat the person.
De enige manier waarop dat kan gebeuren is als de persoon technisch verslaat.
Just like chess, same thing.
Net zoals schaak, net hetzelfde.
You know, all painters, you know, they use, you know, the same paints
Weet je, alle schilders gebruiken dezelfe verf
and the same canvasses, and the same type of brushes.
en dezelfde doeken en dezelfde soort borstels.
But the paintings themselves. Are all just so different.
Maar de schilderijen zelf, zijn allemaal zo anders.
They're so beautiful and so glorious to watch.
Ze zijn zo mooi en heerlijk om naar te kijken.
When we fight that's where we make. our masterpieces.
Wanneer we vechten dat is waar we onze meesterwerken maken.
[♪music♪]
♪[muziek]♪
[metal banging]
[metaal bonst]
- *[Gil] Friday the 13th At the Lake Charles Civic Center*
- [Gil] Vrijdag de 13e in de Lake Charles Stadscentrum,
*Where doing Boudoir number two. We're bringing in a lot of the Lafayette Gladiator Guys.*
Doen we Boudoir nummer twee. We brengen veel Lafayette Gladiator jongens in.
*We're also havin' Dustin Poirier. In our main event and his fighting a guy*
We zullen ook Dustin Poirier in ons hoofd evenement hebben en hij vecht
*by the name of Ronnie Lis.*
een kerel genaamd Ronnie Lis.
*He's a brazilian Jiu-Jitsu black belt.*
Hij is een Braziliaanse Jiu-Jitsu zwarte riem.
*And he's gonna be a serious threat to Dustin.*
En hij zal een serieuze bedreing voor Dustin zijn.
*And we've got Paul Swallow.*
En we hebben Paul Swallow
*Taken on Albert Stainback in his pro debut.*
Die Albert Stainback in his pro debuut opneemt.
[plates clanging]
[borden kletteren]
[Dustin] Right now. I'm just bussing tables and training.
[Dustin] Op het moment ruim ik gewoon tafels af en train.
And I like to train more, I'd like to fight more.
En ik zou graag meer trainen, ik zou graag meer vechten.
I wanna step up my career path.
Ik wil mijn carrière pad opvoeren.
Again not only as a fighter But to feel like I'm doing something.
Nog eens niet alleens als een vechter maar om te voelen dat ik iets doe.
Like becoming an adult I guess. Fighting for my job
Zoals een volwassene worden denk ik. Vechten voor mijn job.
[men talking]
[mannen praten]
- [Albert] This first pro fight. It's actually gonna pay my rent.
- [Albert] Dit eerste pro gevecht. Het gaat eigenlijk wel mijn huur betalen.
We're actually so behind on rent. It's not even funny.
We zijn eigenlijk zo achter op huur. Het is zelfs niet grappig.
And I really hope I'll win this fight.
En ik hoop echt dat ik dit gevecht win.
We used to not be behind on rent.
We waren vroeger niet achter op huur.
My girlfriend is used to be a stripper.
Mijn vriendin was vroeger een stripper
And then like, like, you know, we'd eat sushi everyday.
En dan zo, weet je, we aten elke dag sushi
And we'd freaking you know, go out of town and have fun.
En we zouden dan, weet je, uit de stad gaan, plezier maken.
You know, I kinda feel half of it is my fault--
Weet je, ik voel dat helft ervan mijn fout is--
[train blowing it's horn]
[trein toetert de hoorn]
- *[Tim] I have all kinds of guys come in here.*
- [Tim] Ik heb vele soorten jongens die hier binnenkomen,
Under the impression they're gonna be fighters.
Die onder de indruk zijn dat ze vechters zullen worden.
And I think most guys do not realize, that this is a 40 hour week job.
En ik denk dat de meeste kerels niet beseffen, dit een 40 u per week job is.
This is a grind, you know?
Dit is een karwei, weet je?
What makes great fighters and what makes great champions
Wat goede vechters maakt en wat goede kampioenen maakt
Is the endurance to deal with the grind.
Is het uithoudingsvermogen om de karwei te kunnen handelen.
*You know its 5, 6 days a week of grinding. *
Weet je het is 5, 6 dagen per week zware arbeid.
*2 or 3 hard practices per day out.*
2 of 3 harde praktijken per dag uit.
♪ [music] ♪
♪ [muziek] ♪
- [Albert] Training with Tim has just--
- [Albert] Trainen met Tim heeft gewoon--
it's helped my confidence a lot actually,
Het heeft eigenlijk mijn zelfvertrouwen geholpen,
because he's the only guy I know who'll talk to me
omdat hij de enige kerel is die ik ken die met me zou praten
like I talk to myself in my head.
zoals ik met mezelf in mijn hoofd praat.
And I know he's really just trying to push
En ik weet dat hij gewoon druk probeert uit te oefenen
and see the best "me" I can be.
en om de beste "ik" te kunnen zien.
♪ [music] ♪
♪ [muziek] ♪
*- [Tim] At the end of the day. MMA is an individual sport.*
- [Tim] Op het einde van de dag, MMA is een individuele sport.
*But it is also a team sport.*
Maar het is ook een team sport.
* I can't train myself alone.* *The bags do not hit back.*
Ik kan mezelf niet alleen trainen. De zakken slaan niet terug.
[grunting]
[hijgen]
[male voice] fuck!
[mannelijke stem] fuck!
- [Corey Judice] Tim will definitely let you know. If you're not showing up.
- [Corey Judice] Tim zal je zeker laten weten, wanneer je niet opdaagt,
- *[Albert] * How he feels about it.
Hoe hij zich daarover voelt.
[male voice] move, move, move. step out of there.
[mannelijke stem] beweeg, beweeg, beweeg, stap er uit.
$$ Makes you feel better huh?
$$ Laat het je beter voelen hu?
$$ come on..
$$ Komaan...
[man yelling] Hah!
[man roept] Hah!
[timer ringing]
[timer rinkelt]
- *[Tim] The expectations of our gym are not you have to win every fight.*
- [Tim] De verwachtingen van onze gym zijn niet dat je elk gevecht moet winnen.
*You don't have to win every fight*
Je moet niet elk gevecht winnen.
*But you do have to train for every fight.*
Maar je moet voor elke vechtpartij trainen.
- [Tim] Pier, if you say something like that again.
- [Tim] Pier, als je ooit zoiets nog eens zegt,
You're out of the gym forever. Do you understand?
Ben je voor altijd uit de gym. Goed begrepen?
If you think I'm fucking here. To waste my fucking time on you.
Als je denkt dat ik verdomme hier ben om mijn tijd aan jou te verdoen,
You've lost your mind.
Ben je gek geworden.
You don't do shit for me when I spar with you.
Je doet niets voor me wanneer ik met je spar.
You ever say that to me again. You're out of the gym forever.
Als je dat ooit nog eens tegen me zegt, ben je voor altijd uit de gym.
*You hear me?* - *[Pierre] Yes boss!*
Hoor je mij? -[Pierre] Ja baas!
*[Tim] You need to have some respect.*
[Tim] Je moet wat respect hebben.
*You need to understand, that while you have been doing.*
Je moet begrijpen dat wanneer je wat dan ook aan het doen was,
*Whatever it was you needed to be doing in your time.*
Wat dan ook je moest doen in jouw tijd.
*We've been here working.*
Wij waren hier aan het werken.
*So don't be mad at me, or frustrated with me.*
Dus weest niet kwaad op mij, of gefrustreerd met mij,
*Because you're getting destroyed.*
Omdat je vernietigd wordt.
*You'll found other things to do with your time than come to practice.*
Jij bent degene die andere dingen vond om te doen in plaats van te komen.
You know Corey's fight in Baton Rouge, he took a horrendous beating.
Weet je Corey's gevecht in Baton Rouge, hij nam een verschrikkelijke pak slaag.
You know he got beat on bad, you know.
Hij werd serious geslagen.
- *[announcer] Making his way Into the red corner. Corey Judice*
-[omroeper] Maakt zijn weg naar de rode hoek. Corey Judice.
- [Tim] When we go out there and the music's over.
- [Tim] Wanneer we daar buiten g aan en de muziek is gedaan.
*And you get in there and the door closes.*
En je gaat daar naar binnen en de deur sluit.
I'm not goin' in there with you.
Ik ga daar niet met je binne.
*I can't save you. You have to save yourself.*
Ik kan je niet redden. Je moet jezelf redden.
*Because the chances of you getting hurt in a fight*
Want de kansen dat je gewond raakt in een vechtpartij
before the fight ends are 100% in your career.
voordat het gevecht eindigt zijn 100% in je carrière.
It is not acceptable to try to survive. You must be fighting to win.
Het is niet aanvardbaar om te proberen overleven. Je moet vechten om te winnen.
You must be fighting to finish. 'Cause once you give up,
Je moet vechten om te eindigen. Want eens je opgeeft,
the next 5 or 6 punches are gonna put you in the hospital.
de volgende 5 of 6 slagen zullen je in het ziekenhuis terecht brengen.
You can never give up.
Je kan nooit opgeven.
You must fight until you can't physically fight anymore.
Je moet vechten totdat je fysiek niet meer kan vechten.
Or until you win.
Of totdat je wint.
-*[announcer] In the red corner.. Corey Judice*
-[omroeper] In de rode hoek...Corey Judice.
[Crowd cheering]
[Menigte juicht]
[Tim] I'm glad he won the fight. And you know of course...
[Tim] Ik ben blij dat hij de vechtpartij won. En dat weet je natuurlijk wel...
But I'm more proud that he made it through there.
Maar ik ben vooral fier dat hij het daar doorheen maakte.
You know... And he got beat up a little bit.
Weet je...hij werdt een beetje geslagen
And he got black eye and stuff.
En hij kreeg een blauw oog en zo.
But you know, he was in some dangerous position a couple times.
Maar weet je, hij was een paar keer in gevaarlijke posities
And because of the fact that we live in dangerous position at the gym.
En omdat we in een gevaarlijke positie in de gym leven
You know he was able to defend himself.
was hij in staat om zichzelf te verdedigen.
And he was able to get out.
En hij was in staat om eruit te komen.
And he was able to not sustain the type of damage.
En hij was in staat om niet het soort schade
That could have render him hurt really bad.
Op te lopen dat hem heel erg gewond zou kunnen laten.
You know, and it's my responsibility
En het is mijn verantwoordelijkheid
to know they're ready to deal with what happen.
om te weten dat ze klaar zijn om wat er gebeurd is te behandelen.
So, I just take it seriously and--
Dus ik neem het serieus en--
but, I ain't sparred with the guy in 2 weeks. He's got fight this week.
maar, ik heb al 2 weken niet met de kerel gespart. Hij heeft een gevecht deze week.
You know sometimes. I'm too rough maybe...
Weet je soms ben ik misschien te ruw...
And sometimes I go,
En soms ga ik,
you know, maybe over the line.
weet je wel, over de lijn.
But you know what. They don't get hurt.
Maar dat weet je. Ze geraken niet gewond
And they beat the crap out of people.
en ze slaan de stront uit mensen.
[gong clanging]
[gong klettert]
- [Albert ] My dad used to beat my mom. Senseless.
= [Albert] Mijn vader sloeg mijn moeder vroeger. Zinloos.
And and I always put that in my head whenever I think about certain things.
En ik heb dat altijd in mijn hoofd wanneer ik aan zekere dingen denk.
You know, when I go to my angry place. I guess.
Je weet wel, wanneer ik naar mijn boze plaats ga. Denk ik.
He had my mom by the throat. He picked her up.
Hij had mijn ma bij de keel. Hij pakte haar op.
And blood was running down his arm out of her mouth.
En bloed stroomde over zijn arm vanuit haar mond.
'Cause he was like digging into her mouth with his thumbs.
Want hij was in haar mond aan het graven met met zijn duimen
And shit like that.
en zulke dingen.
And then, [clears throat] , my dad shot himself when I was 9.
En toen [schraapt keel], schoot mijn vader zichzelf toen ik 9 was.
And my mom went off on a big alcoholic binge.
En mijn moeder ging op een grote alcholische bui.
So there was a lot of stuff that happened,
Dus er was veel dat was gebeurd.
I guess, you could say that made me kinda wanna fight.
Ik denk dat je kan zeggen dat dat maakte dat ik wou vechten.
I honestly attribute me wanting to fight,
Eerlijk gezegd schrijf ik mijn wil om te vechten toe aan,
if I have to give some kind of Freudian guess at it,
als ik een soort van Freudiane gok er op moet doen,
It is to--I wanted to be a defender.
Is het om--Ik wou een verdediger zijn.
♪ [music] ♪
♪ [muziek ♪
I believe life is all about balance.
Ik geloof dat het leven allemaal rond balans draait.
And violence is part of that balance.
En geweld is een deel van die balans.
[birds chirping]
[vogels tjirpen]
- [Dustin] When somebody ask me. What you do for a living?
- [Dustin] Wanneer iemand me vraagt, wat verdient u uw boterham mee?
I don't say, *I'm a professional fighter.*
Zeg ik niet, Ik ben een professionele vechter.
I say,"I work in Cane and Co. I drive a delivery truck."
Ik zeg, "Ik werk in Cane and Co. Ik rijdt een vrachtwagen."
You know, I can't lie to somebody and say "I'm a professional fighter."
Ik kan niet tegen iemand liegen en zeggen "Ik ben een professionele vechter."
I might make money doing it but is that my profession?
Ik verdien wel geld door dat te doen maar is het wel mijn beroep?
Is that what I do to provide for me and my wife?
Is het wat ik doe om voor mij en mijn vrouw te verstrekken?
I'm trying to make it that.
Ik probeer dat te doen.
- [Jere Folley Chaisou]
-[Jere Folley Chaisou]
Back then if you wrote left, they try to make you right with it.
Toen als je links schreef, probeerden ze je rechts te laten schrijven.
- [Dustin Forrier] Do I always right left? - [Jere Folley Chaisou] Yeah.
- [Dustin Poirier] Schrijf ik altijd links? - [Jere Folley Chaisou] Ja.
- [Dustin Forrier] Really?
- [Dustin Poirier] Echt?
Yup.
Yup.
[Dustin Forrier] No way
[Dustin Poirier] No way
I'm telling you
Ik zeg het u
He's accomplished so much.
Hij volbracht zoveel.
He went from this alcoholic kid to, you know, professional fighter.
Hij ging van dit alcoholisch kind naar, weet je, een professionele vechter.
He owns his own home, he works just minimally,
Hij bezit zijn huis, hij werkt maar minimaal,
Just a few hours. Just to keep his benefits.
Maar een paar uren, Alleen om zijn voordelen te behouden.
He's my hero and he's gonna do it. I know that he is..
Hij is mijn held en hij zal het doen ik weet dat hij...
He's gonna be amazing. He's gonna be a household name.
Dat hij geweldig zal zijn. Hij zal een huishouding naam zijn.
♪ [music] ♪
♪ [muziek] ♪
- [Gil] If you can't sell tickets I can't use you.
- [Gil] Als je geen tickets kunt verkopen kan ik je niet gebruiken.
*[man on phone] Go down baby, go down.*
[man aan de telefoon] Daal baby, daal.
Because I can't make money.
Want ik kan geen geld verdienen.
If I gotta pay a fighter $15000, a $1000 to show up.
Als ik een vechter $1500, een $1000 moet betalen om te komen,
Another $1000 to win. But he can't sell worth $4000 worth of tickets.
Nog eens $1000 om te winnen. Maar hij kan geen $4000 in waarde tickets verkopen.
*[man on phone] You should have - Will you pay somebody that hard. *
[Man aan de telefoon] Je zou moeten - Betaal je iemand dat moeilijk,
Most of the time if they're really good. They won't show.
Meestal als ze zeer goed zijn, zullen ze niet opdagen.
You know they just. They didn't know how to bring the crawl.
Weet je ze weten gewoon niet hoe de kruip te brengen.
[man on phone] I - I know
[man aan de telefoon] Ik weet het.
The bite of my own ass part of it. Is that.
De beet van mijn eigen kont deel ervan is dat,
I have to hyped that fighter up so much.
Ik moet die vechter zo veel ophypen.
That they're friends and families start to make them believe it.
Dat hun vrienden en families hen start te laten geloven.
They start believing it.
Ze beginnen te geloven.
They come to me, demanding more money.
Ze komen naar me, eisen meer geld.
Because they honestly believe that their worth it.
Omdat zij eerlijk geloven dat ze de moeite waard zijn.
Because everyone else tells them that they're the 2nd coming.
Omdat iedereen hen vertelt dat ze de tweede komst zijn.
And little do they know. You're not the 2nd coming.
En weinig weten ze. Je bent niet de tweede komst.
You're exactly what I made you to be.
Je bent precies wat ik je gemaakt heb.
I've promoted you this way. I've made you this way.
Ik heb je op deze manier bevorderd. Ik heb je op deze manier gemaakt.
I can take Gary Coleman and turn and take Gary Coleman.
Ik kan Gary Coleman nemen en draai en Gary Coleman nemen.
And promote him properly.
En hem goed bevorderen.
And everybody will come to see Gary Coleman fight.
En iedereen zal komen om Gary Coleman te zien vechten.
So you're no more special than he is. - *And you know what I'd make a killing*
Dus bent je niet meer special dan hij is. - En weet je wat ik zou een moord doen.
*[man on phone] Cause he is - Looks phenomenal.*
[man aan de telefoon] Want hij is - ziet er fenomenaal uit.
- [Albert ] I'm the main event? - *[Gil] Not, you're semi.*
-[Albert] Ik ben het hoofd evenement? - [Gil] Nee, je bent semi.
- [Albert] Oh semi, that's cool, open it up for Dustin always love it.
- [Albert] Oh semi, dat is cool, open het hoog voor Dustin, ik hou er altijd van.
- *[Gil] Need to... yeah... Need to provide...*
- [Gil] Moet... Ja... Moet verstrekken...
- *[male voice] Semi is what you are.*
- [mannelijke stem] Semi is wat je bent.
- Semi pro.
-Semi pro.
- [male voice] Yup. - [Gil] Hep. B and C results.
-[mannelijke stem] Yup. -[Gil] Hep. B en C resultaten.
- [male voice] ♪ Love me sexy ♪
-[mannelijke stem] ♪ Love me sexy ♪
- [Gil] And HIV result no more than 6 month old.
- [Gil] En HIV resultaat niet meer dan 6 maanden oud.
- [Albert] I'd just ask you bout that.
-[Albert] Ik wou u daar net over vragen.
I got some results but the 13th, they will be officially 3 days overdue.
Ik heb enkele resultaten voor de 13e, ze zullen officieel 3 dagen te laat zijn.
Do you want me to go ahead and...? - [Gil] No, you have to.
Wil je dat ik verder ga en...? -[Gil] Nee, je moet.
Yeah, they're over 6 months.
Ja, ze zijn meer dan 6 maanden.
- [Albert] I got you homes. You put "back" on there didn't you?
- [Albert] Je schreef daar "back"op ja?
- [Gil] "Stain-back." - [Albert] There we go.
-[Gil] "Stain-back." -[Albert] Daar gaan we.
- [Gil] And we'll make a copy of this if there's a machine in here.
-[Gil] En we maken een kopie hiervan als er hier een machine is.
But I don't think there is
Maar ik denk het niet.
- [Albert] I'm sure if I'm gonna weigh in,
- [Albert] Ik weet zeker dat als ik ga af wegen,
I weigh in at 155 pounds. Got you, no problem.
Ik 70 kg ga wegen. Heb het, geen probleem.
[paper flipping] [pen screeching]
[papier omdraaien] [pen gekrijs]
♪ [music] ♪
♪ [muziek] ♪
- [Dustin] I'm ready to do it.
-[Dustin] ik ben er klaar voor.
I'm ready to fight. I'll fight tonight if I could.
Ik ben klaar om te vechten. Ik zou vanavond vechten als ik kon.
If I have to fight tonight, I'd be ready to go.
Als ik vanavond moest vechten, zou ik er klaar voor zijn.
Of course, after I drink a little bit and not be so dizzy.
Natuurlijk, nadat ik een beetje drink en niet zo duizilig ben.
I'm mentally ready to fight. Physically, hurting.
Ik ben mentaal klaar om te vechten. Fysiek, doet het pijn.
But this is part of it.
Maar dit is er onderdeel van.
The fight already started for me. This is the fight right now.
De strijd begon al voor mij. Dit is nu de strijd.
It's part of the fight
Het is onderdeel van de strijd.
Tomorrow about 1 o'clock,12 o'clock. I'll be done. I'll be about 155.
Morgen ongeveer 1 uur, 12 uur. Zal ik klaar zijn. Ik zal ongeveer 70 kg zijn.
Just gotta keep sweating.
Gewoon blijven zweten.
♪ [music] ♪
♪ [muziek] ♪
[mans voice] stop! stop!
[man's stem] Stop! Stop!
[people talking]
[mensen praten]
-* [Gil's wife] Let's see, say's the woman on the telephone *
- [Gil's vrouw] Laten we eens kijken, zegt de vrouw aan de telefoon
wanted to know exactly what this, Louisiana versus Florida event was all about.
wilde weten wat dit, Louisiana versus Florida evenement was.
Telling her it was mixed martial arts Didn't seem to answer that question.
Zei haar dat 't gemixte vechtsport is. Dat bleek die vraag niet te beantwoorden.
It's cage fighting,
Het is kooi vechten,
Gillory said it wasn't to say the least what she wanted to hear.
Gillory zei dat het niet op het minst was wat ze wilde horen.
She said, "That's disgusting. I wanna do everything in my power
Ze zei: "Dat is walgelijk. Ik wil alles binnen mijn macht doen
"To make sure this never comes back here."
Om er zeker van te zijn dat dit nooit meer naar hier komt."
I don't know if that's good or bad but it starts off with that.
Ik weet niet of dat goed of slecht is, maar het begint zo.
- *[Gil] It's good, all press is good.*
- [Gil] Het is goed, alle pers is goed.
*All right, Dustin Poirier, main event 155 pounds Gladiator Academy.*
Oke, Dustin Poirier, hoofd evenement 70 kg Gladiator Academie.
- *[male voice] Hey, Gil. Grey wants to know where to get his ticket from?*
- [mannelijke stem] Hey, Gil. Grey wil weten waar hij zijn ticket kan halen?
* [Gil] One fifty-four point oh.* Who?
[Gil] Een vierenvijftig punt nul. Wie?
- *[male voice] Grey.*
- [mannelijke stem] Grey.
- [Gil] Who's Grey?
-[Gil] Wij is Grey?
No,no. Civic center.
Nee, nee. Stadscentrum.
*Ronnie, are you ready, bro?*
Ronnie, bent je klaar, bro?
- [Gil] One fifty three. Main event. Guys we got a fight.
-[Gil] Een vijftig drie. Hoofdevenement. Jongens we hebben een gevecht.
- * [male voice] Yeah.*
- [mannelijke stem] Ja.
-* [Gil] Semi main event, 155 pounds*
- [Gil] Semi hooefdevenement, 70 kg.
- [Albert ] We're the semi! We're like the opening band.
-[Albert] We zijn de semi! We zijn net de opening band.
-*[male voice] Yeah*
- [mannelijke stem] Ja
[phone ringing]
[telefoon rinkelt]
- *[Gil] . Who's that?*
- [Gil] Wie is dat?
- *[male voice] You're old man.* - *[Gil] Answer it.*
- [mannelijke stem] Je oude man. - [Gil] Antwoord het.
[men talking]
[mannen praten]
- [Gil] One fifty four point two. Okay, yeah, tell them thanks.
-[Gil] Een vijftig vier punt twee. Oke, ja, zeg ze bedankt.
- *One fifty-two point eight.*
- Één tweeënvijftig punt acht.
Good job boys.
Goed werk jongens.
[chewing]
[kauwen]
- That's not monkey.
-Dat is niet aap.
[slurping]
[slurpen]
Oh God.
Oh God.
♪ [music] ♪
♪ [muziek] ♪
- [foreign language] I'm a victor in 1 minute.
-[vreemde taal] Ik ben een winnaar in 1 minuut.
Be careful my opponent
Wees voorzichtig mijn tegenstander.
Dustin is gonna be in for a tough fight.
Dustin zit in voor een zware strijd.
They wanted a tough opponent, I got them a tough opponents
Ze wilden een taaie tegenstander,ik heb hen een taaie tegenstanders gehaald.
So we're gonna see exactly what happens with them tomorrow.
Dus gaan we zien precies wat er gebeurt met hen morgen.
- [Albert] For my first pro fight. I'll be making you know 500 show and five to win.
- [Albert] Voor m'n eerste pro gevecht, ga ik 500 verdienen om op te dagen
This is real now. This isn't some amateur fight. You know...
en 500 om te winnen.Dit is echt nu. Dit is niet een amateur strijd. Weet je...
From every move I make from now on. Will determine if I can eat.
Elke beweging van nu af aan, zal bepalen of ik kan eten.
I know I have. You know, moments of worry. But...
Ik weet dat ik weet je, momenten van zorg heb. Maar...
When you step into that cage, you prove it to yourself.
Wanneer je die kooi binnenstapt, bewijs je aan jezelf.
And I've proven it to myself 17 times.
En ik heb het al 17 keer aan mezelf bewezen.
That I've got what it takes to do this. And I'm gonna do it.
Dat ik heb wat nodig is om dit te doen. En ik ga het doen.
- This is a mixed crowd. We're gonna have kids
- Dit is een gemengde menigte. Er zullen kinderen zijn,
We're gonna have ladies
Er zullen dames zijn
We're gonna have lots of people here.
We gaan hier veel mensen hebben.
It's not gonna be in a bar room situation.
Het zal niet in een bar kamer situatie zijn.
So keep you language down. I don't wanna hear any 4 letter words. Okay?
Dus hou je taal naar beneden. Ik wil geen 4 letter woorden horen. Ok?
In an event you have to go to the hospital.
In de gebeurtenis dat je naar het ziekenhuis moet,
Let the doctor determine if you're gonna go to the hospital or not.
Laat de arts bepalen of je naar het ziekenhuis gaat of niet.
Okay?
Ok?
You discuss it with the doctor.If you feel bad, if you got a major injury.
Je bespreekt het met de dokter. Als je je slecht voelt, als je een ernstige
You feel like you got something seriously wrong with you.
verwonding hebt. Je voelt je alsof er iets serieus mis met je is.
Let the doctor discuss that with the EMT's and the ambulance people.
Laat de arts dat bespreken met de EMT en de ambulance mensen.
And coordinate.
En coördineer.
Don't just in an ambulance and say, "Take me to the hospital."
Ga niet alleen in een ambulance en zeg: "Breng me naar het ziekenhuis."
[beep, beep, beep]
[biep, biep biep]
- [Tim] There's an arrogance in Brazil, in a lot of levels. And--
- [Tim] Er is een arrogantie in Brazilië, in veel niveaus. en -
When it comes to Jiu-Jitsu. I've been there a few times to train. And--
Als het gaat om Jiu-Jitsu. Ik ben er een paar keren geweest om te trainen en--
You know sometimes those guys since you know, Jiu-Jitsu kinda--
Weet je soms die jongens, omdat je weet, Jiu-Jitsu soort van--
really kinda started it all on a lot of levels.
echt nogal begon het allemaal op veel niveaus.
They believe when they come over here,
Zij geloven wanneer zij hier komen,
we're just not necessarily ready for them.
we zijn gewoon niet noodzakelijk klaar voor hen.
And, you know, they're just gonna really show us what a real fighter is about.
En weet je, ze gaan ons gewoon laten zien wat een echte vechter allemaal om draait.
And, you know that might have been the case many years ago,
En weet je, misschien was dat zo vele jaren geleden,
but it's not the case anymore, you know...
maar dat is niet het geval meer, weet je...
Dustin's a young kid in South Louisiana.
Dustin is een jonge kerel in Zuid-Louisiana.
But he's got 2 black belts at his disposal.
Maar hij heeft 2 zwarte gordels tot zijn beschikking.
That he trains in regularly and coming to America
Die hij regelmatig in traint en naar Amerika komen
and fighting a guy who's never seen Jiu-Jitsu,
en een kerel vechten die nog nooit Jiu-Jitsu gezien heeft.
It's not a real, not real scenario anymore.
Het is niet echt, geen echt scenario meer.
And the fact the guys thinks that, indicates to me that,
En het feit dat de jongens dat denken, geeft mij aan dat,
Maybe he's not necessarily been around fighting for that--
Misschien is hij niet per se al zolang
that long around here.
hier aan het vechten.
And I think that Dustin's opponent may need to learn that the hard way tonight.
En ik denk dat Dustin's tegenstander dat vanavond wellicht op harde manier leert,
- [Dustin] I just want to crack him on his chin.
-[Dustin] Ik wil hem gewoon op zijn kin barsten.
[crowd cheering]
[menigte juicht]
- [Gil] Jesus Christ! What have we got ourselves into?
-[Gil] Jezus Christus! Wat hebben we onszelf nu ingestoken?
[male voice] I know, I gotta have music go.
[mannelijke stem] Ik weet het, ik ga muziek moet hebben.
[crowd cheering]
[menigte juicht]
[yelling]
[schreeuwen]
♪ [music] ♪
♪ [muziek] ♪
[crowd clapping]
[menigte klapt]
- What's on my mind? What's on my mind is I'm here to win.
- Wat is aan mijn gedachten? Wat aan mijn gedachten is dat ik hier ben om te winnen.
You're in the way of my destiny. Get out of my way.
Je bent in de weg van mijn lot. Ga uit mijn weg.
I'm the better fighter. I'm here to win
Ik ben de betere vechter. Ik ben hier om te winnen
[Gil] Use them hands, Albert
[Gil] Gebruik je handen, Albert
- [Tim] When Albert was kid I sure he never saw the lines in his color book.
-[Tim] Toen Albert een kind was ben ik zeker dat hij nooit de lijnen in zijn
His fighting is not neat, it's not pretty but he defintely colors the whole page.
kleurboek zag. Zijn vechten is niet netjes, het is niet mooi maar hij kleurt
Just like that kid you know. He fights hard, he never quits.
zeker de hele pagina. Net zoals dat kind je kent. Hij vecht hard, hij stopt nooit.
He fights to finish you. No matter what he fights to finish.
Hij vecht om je te eindigen. Doet er niet toe wat hij vecht om te voltooien.
[crowd cheering]
[menigte juicht]
- [Albert] When the fears of losing
-[Albert] Wanneer de vrees om te verliezen
or the fears of not being able to pursue my career
of de vrees om mijn carrière niet te kunnen navolgen
or getting hurt start going to my head,
of gewond raken door mijn hoofd begint te malen,
there's a voice in my head that says, you know, "What are you doing?
er is een stem in mijn hoofd dat zegt, weet je, 'Wat ben je aan het doen?
You could get hurt for life, you could fail."
Je zou kunnen gewond raken voor het leven, je kan falen. "
You know, when that fear and doubt comes up, even that voice comes out.
Wanneer die angst en twijfel opkomt, zelfs die stem naar buiten komt.
It's almost like a person. I beat the fuck out of it.
Het is bijna als een persoon. Ik sla er de fuck uit.
You know, I'd kick it down the stairs. You know, I chain it to the basement.
Weet je, ik zou het van de trap schoppen. Ik zou het in de kelder vastketenen.
Kick it a few more times for good measure.
Kick het een paar keer voor goede maatregel.
Then I head back upstairs and I lock that door.
Dan ga ik terug naar boven en ik sluit die deur.
Because I will not have that fear stop me from doing what I wanna do.
Want ik wil niet dat die angst me stopt van wat ik wil doen.
[crowd cheering]
[menigte juicht]
*[announcer] Stop picking accidents 350. One of the first three rounds*
[omroeper] Stop met ongevallen 350 pikken. Een van de eerste drie rondes
*In the blue corner, representing Gladiators academy,*
In de blauwe hoek, vertegenwoordigt Gladiatoren Academie,
*Albert Stainback!*
Albert Stainback!
[crowd mixed cheering and booing]
[menigte gemengd gejuich en gejoel]
- Yeah, I'd love a rematch. I mean, I spent 4 and half minutes
-Ja, ik zou graag een rematch doen. Ik bedoel, ik heb 4 en een half minuten
on top of the guy. Pounded him out, trying to choke him.
op die kerel gezeten. Sloeg hem, hem proberen te stikken.
Next time I'd make sure I'd do that for 15 minutes not just four and half.
Volgende keer zou ik ervoor zorgen dat ik het doe voor 15 minuten niet slechts
You know, but what you gonna do? You don't complain about it.
vier en een half. Maar wat ga je doen? Je klaagt er niet over.
You go back to the gym and start training.
Je gaat terug naar de gym en begint te trainen.
- [announcer] Alright, ladies and gentlemen.
-[omroeper] Ok, dames en heren.
This your tenth and final bout-- is the main event!
Dit uw tiende en laatste wedstrijd -- is het hoofdevenement!
- [Dustin] It's just kinda crazy. I'm really nervous before.
-[Dustin] Het is gewoon een beetje gek. Ik ben echt nerveus vooraf.
Cause I've played the fight over my head.
Omdat ik de vechtpartij al in mijn hoofd heb afgespeeld.
Like this guy I'm about to fight.
Zoals die kerel die ik ga vechten.
Men, I've fought him a million times already In my head.
Man, ik heb hem al een miljoen keer in mijn hoofd gevochten.
Just in this last month. You know?
Enkel in deze laatste maand. Weet je?
I've beat him a million times. Already in my head.
Ik heb hem al een miljoen keer in mijn hoofd verslaan.
[thud, thud, thud]
[plof, plof, plof]
When it's time to walk out there to the cage.
Wanner het tijd is om daar buiten naar de kooi te lopen,
It's just the time to actually do it.
Het is gewoon de tijd om het daadwerkelijk doen.
I kinda feel full of joy.
Ik voel me vol vreugde.
Man, when I'm walking to the cage. I'm happy.
Man, wanneer ik naar de kooi loop, ben ik gelukkig.
[Dustin] HAH!
[Dustin] HAH!
- [announcer] Dustin Poirier. Three five minute rounds.
-[omroeper] Dustin Poirier. Drie vijf minuten rondes.
One fifty five pound weight division
Zeventig kilo gewicht divisie.
♪ [music] ♪
♪ [muziek] ♪
[referee] Don't wanna fight.
[scheidsrechter] Wil niet vechten.
[crowd cheering]
[menigte juicht]
-*[male voice] Aint got no stand up. *
- [mannelijke stem] Heeft geen opstaan.
[thud, thud, thud]
[plof, plof, plof]
-*[Gil] Get him Dustin. Beautiful.*
- [Gil] Krijg hem Dustin. Mooi zo.
[slam] Uhmp! Uhmp!
[bons] Uhmp! Uhmp!
*[crowd screaming]*
[menigte schreeuwt]
[mans voice] Elbows hold them, elbow relax.
[man's stem] Ellebogen houd ze, elleboog ontspannen.
[floor banging]
[vloer bonzen]
[crowd cheering]
[menigte juicht]
[crowd yelling]
[menigte schreeuwt]
[man yelling] Get back up!
[man schreeuwt] Sta terug op!
[slam, slam, slam]
[bons, bons ,bons]
[Tim] Be more respectful next time
[Tim] Volgende keer wees meer respectvol.
- [Dustin] Hey K. Your hand pop. And pop, pop, pop!
-[Dustin] Hey K. Uw hand pop. En pop, pop, pop!
-* [referee] You're on the wrong side.*
- [scheidsrechter] Je bent aan de verkeerde kant.
- *[announcer] Fighters to the center of the ring. *
- [omroeper] Vechters naar het midden van de ring.
*We go to the official score card.*
We gaan naar de officiële scorekaart.
*You're winner after 354 seconds of the first round by way of tap out,*
Je bent winnaar na 354 seconden van de eerste ronde door middel van onttrekken,
*In the red corner Dustin Poirier!*
In de rode hoek Dustin Poirier!
*[man talking] Dude, Jiu-jitsu was good.*
[man praat] Jongens, Jiu-jitsu was goed.
- [Dustin] Oh yeah, it was. I was ice skating through them heel hooks.
-[Dustin] Oh ja, het was. Ik was aan het schaatsen door die hak haken.
He had it for a second a heel hook but I turned it over
Hij had het voor een seconde die hiel haak maar ik draaide het over
and he went into a knee bar.
en hij ging in een knie-bar.
- *[Tim] So how long did that take, Dustin?*
- [Tim] Hoe lang duurde dat, Dustin?
-Fifty seven seconds. What he said is, he's gonna beat me in a minute.
-Zevenenvijftig seconden. Wat hij zei is, dat hij me in een minuut ging verslaan.
So you gotta watch out what you say sometimes.
Dus moet je soms oppassen wat je zegt.
You gotta eat your words you know.
U moet uw woorden eten, weet je.
- At his own game baby. Oh my God! Hey!
-In zijn eigen spel baby. O jee! Hey!
[Crowd laughing]
[Menigte lacht]
- History is written by the victor, ultimately--
-Geschiedenis isuiteindelijk geschreven door de overwinnaar--
I mean, because the losers dead.
Ik bedoel, omdat de verliezer dood is.
He wants a rematch. So he wants me at my best.
Hij wil een rematch. Dus hij wil me op mijn beste.
So I'll give him "Me" at my best.
Dus geef ik hem "Ik" op mijn beste.
I've noticed that when I'm not training.
Ik heb dat gemerkt wanneer ik niet aan het trainen ben.
And I'm not on the path to being a great fighter,
En ik ben niet op de weg om een geweldige vechter te worden,
like I want to be, like I tell everybody I want to be,
Als ik wil worden, zoals ik iedereen vertel ik wil worden,
like I tell myself I want to be,
zoals ik mezelf vertel ik wil worden,
it seems that's when the bad shit in my life happens.
het lijkt erop dat wanneer de slechte dingen in mijn leven gebeuren.
That seems like that's when all-- everything starts going to shit.
Dat lijkt alsof dat is wanneer al--alles begint naar beneden te gaan.
And when I'm doing what I'm suppose to be doing
En wanneer ik doe wat ik moet doen
to be a great fighter. Nothing can go wrong in my life.
om een geweldige vechter te zijn. Niets kan misgaan in mijn leven.
♪ [drum beats] ♪
♪ [drum beats] ♪
- [Gil] Hey guys! How ya all doin?
-[Gil] Hey jongens! Hoe gaat het met jullie?
- Hey, we're doing a show at the Cajundome
-Hey, we doen een show in de Cajundome
for caged fighting on March 6.
voor kooivechten op 6 maart.
I don't know if you're all into it but if you all are, please come by
Ik weet niet of je er allemaal in bent maar als je er al bent, kom het
and come by, check it out, okay?
uitchecken, ok?
All right you all.
Ok, allemaal.
Remember how the circus would come to town when you're a kid?
Herinner je hoe het circus naar je stad kwam toen je een kind was?
They'd unload the animals at the train station and parade them through town.
Ze zouden de dieren uitladen op het station en hen door de stad paraderen.
They'd use the elephants as billboards.
Ze zou de olifanten gebruiken als reclameborden.
They'd have the clowns and midgets walking behind creating excitement.
De clowns en dwergen liepen erna om voor opwinding te zorgen.
Well, I do the same thing, only my car is my elephant
Nou, ik doe het zelfde ding, maar mijn auto is mijn olifant
and postcards are my midgets.
en postkaarten zijn mijn dwergen.
[crowd screaming] Throw me something!
[menigte schreeuwt] Gooi me iets!
[whistle blowing]
[fluit blaast]
♪ [band music] ♪
♪ [band muziek] ♪
[thump, thump, thump]
[bons, bons, bons]
[thud, thud, thud]
[plof, plof, plof]
[muttering]
[mompelen]
I'm fighting Derrick Krantz..
Ik vecht tegen Derrick Krantz..
He's a pretty young, a year or two older than me.
Hij is redelijk jong, een jaar of twee ouder dan ik.
I think he might be 22 years old He's got a lot of fights.
Ik denk dat hij misschien 22 jaar oud is, die heeft een heleboel gevechten.
That doesn't intimidate me, you know? I know what my hands can do too.
Dat intimideert mij niet, weet je? Ik weet wat mijn handen kunnen doen.
I'm gonna meet him in the middle of the cage and we're gonna fight.
Ik ga om hem in het midden van de kooi ontmoeten en we gaan vechten.
When you have two guys like that meet up in the cage in front of audience.
Wanneer je twee kerels hebt die zo elkaar in de kooi ontmoeten voor het publiek
Man, you have no choice but to have a great fight.
Man, hebt je geen andere keuze dan een goed gevecht te hebben.
And you know two guys who go at each other like that
En weet je twee jongens die zo tegen elkaar op gaan
neither of us is gonna back down.
geen van ons zal zich terugtrekken.
And that's for sure you're gonna see fireworks you know.
En dat is zeker je gaat vuurwerk zien.
It's gonna be great fight to watch.
Het gaat een goede vechtpartij worden om naar te kijken.
- [Albert] As of late, you know I've been showing up at the gym
-[Albert] De laatste tijd, weet je ik daag op in de gym
maybe three times a week and hitting two or three classes or one, you know.
misschien drie keer per week en twee of drie klassen volgen of een , weet je.
So it's not been very well, like, I said, a lot of people go to the gym
Dus het is niet erg goed geweest, zoals ik zei, veel mensen gaan naar de gym
and they train to get rid of stress.
en trainen ze om zich te ontdoen van stress.
And, I don't know. I'm just different.
En ik weet niet. Ik ben gewoon anders.
You know when something is on my mind it's hard for me to train.
Wanneer iets aan mijn gedachten is, is het moeilijk voor mij om te trainen.
So that's been my problem lately. Just you know, lot of personal problems.
Dus dat was mijn probleem de laatste tijd. Gewoon, veel persoonlijke problemen.
Relationship wise. You know, things aren't working out.
Relatie-wijs. Weet je, dingen werken niet uit.
And like I said that's weight on me that I've been carrying into the gym.
En zoals ik al zei dat gewicht op me dat ik naar de gym breng,
I think the big problem was that I felt out of control with my last,
Ik denk dat het grote probleem was dat ik me buiten controle voelde bij m'n laatste,
you know, the situation with Chelsea, with my ex-girlfriend and everything.
weet je, de situatie met Chelsea, met mijn ex-vriendin en zo.
I felt very out of control and it just-- it bothered me. It threw me off.
Ik voelde me zeer buiten controle en het --het hinderde me. Het gooide me af.
But now, I'm in one of those situations where everything's up to me,
Maar nu ben ik in een van die situaties waar alles aan mij is,
you know, if I don't have a place to live, that's on me.
weet je, als ik geen plek heb om te wonen, dat is aan mij.
If I don't win fights or I don't, you know I don't perform well, that's all on me.
Als ik geen gevechten win of ik niet, goed doe, dat is allemaal aan mij.
You know, I don't have anything in my way that anyone else doesn't.
Weet je, ik heb niets in mijn manier dat iemand anders dat niet doet.
You know what I'm saying?
Begrijp je wat ik zeg?
So let's see what happens.
Dus laten we zien wat er gebeurt.
[Door closing]
[Deur gaat dicht]
♪ [music] ♪
♪ [muziek] ♪
- *[Dustin] When you devout yourself to something like I do fighting,*
- [Dustin] Wanneer je jezelf aan iets wijdt, zoals ik met vechten,
it just changes. It drowns out all the other stuff going on.
verandert het. Het verdrinkt alle andere dingen die omgaan.
It kinda helps me focus on one thing, it's almost like natural now
Het helpt me om op een ding te focussen, het is bijna natuurlijk
to do the right things.
om de juiste dingen te doen.
I'm really in touch with my body. I think my body knows when its time
Ik ben echt in contact met mijn lichaam. Ik denk dat mijn lichaam weet wanneer
to prepare for a fight.
het tijd is om voor een vechtpartij voor te bereiden.
And get it sharp and get it crisp and get it read to go to the battle.
En krijg het scherp en krijg het knapperig en krijg het kaalr voor de strijd.
When it's time to fight my weapons are ready.
Mijn wapens zijn klaar wanneer het tijd is om te vechten.
- *[Tim] Albert and I missing his practice is all so crazy. *
- [Tim] Albert en ik die zijn oefening missen is zo gek.
He maybe came one time in three weeks and so, he call me today
Misschien kwam hij één keer in drie weken en zo, hij belde me vandaag
and says he's not ready to fight, which he's not but I told him
en zegt dat hij niet klaar is te vechten, en dat is hij niet, maar ik vertelde hem
he doesn't have the ability to pull out right now because it's up to Gil.
Hij beschikt niet over de mogelijkheid om nu terug te trekken omdat dat aan Gil is.
You already gave you word, it's two weeks outs.
Je gaf al je woord, het is twee weken uit.
You have another professional training to fight you.
Je hebt nog een andere professionele training om je te vechten.
This isn't an amateur fight, you know?
Dit is geen amateur vechtpartij, weet je?
There's another guy who's got money on the line
Er is een andere kerel die geld op de lijn heeft
and bills on the line,
en rekeningen op de lijn,
you just can't pull out on that guy because you had too much drama.
je kan je niet gewoon terugtrekken omdat je te veel drama hebt gehad.
[train honking]
[train toetert]
- Okay so he told you he still doesn't know
-Ok, dus hij vertelde je dat hij nog niet weet
if he wants to fight or not?
Of hij wil vechten of niet?
- He doesn't want to or does he?
-Hij wil niet of wel?
- Here's the thing, just don't even talk to him no more.
- Hier is het, praat gewoon niet meer met hem.
- He talked to me, yeah.
- Hij sprak met mij, ja.
- If you can find him, find Swallow an opponent,
- Als je hem kunt vinden, zoek Swallow een tegenstander,
- I can.
- Ik kan dat.
- then that guy needs to fight Paul.
- dan die kerel moet Paul vechten.
- Okay that's none on--
-Ok dat is geen op--
- If you can't fight Paul Swallow an opponent,
-Als je Paul Swallow geen tegenstander kan vinden,
I'll make Albert fight, cause its--
Laat ik Albert vechten, want het is--
I'm not gonna let Paul Swallow lose the fight.
Ik ga Paul Swallow het gevecht niet laten verliezen.
- Right.
- Juist.
- You know that, that has to be, you know, rewarded or penalized
- Je weet dat, dat moet worden, weet je, beloond of bestraft
on some level from a team perspective, you know?
op een bepaald niveau vanuit het perspectief van een team weet je?
[train honking]
[train toetert]
- *[Gil] We all need to be on the same page, okay?*
- [Gil] We moeten allemaal op dezelfde pagina zijn,ok?
- Okay.
-Ok.
- Tim says that you're not fighting.
-Tim zegt dat je niet vecht.
You're saying, you don't know if you're fighting.
Je zegt, je weet niet of je gaat vechten.
I'm saying you better off not fighting,
Ik zeg je bent beter af niet te vechten,
I'm also saying that if you're gonna fight.
Ik zeg ook dat als je gaat vechten,
I understand, however, I don't recommend it
Ik begrijp het, maar ik beveel het niet
unless absolutely need the money, okay?
tenzij je het geld absoluut nodig hebt,ok?
Tim asked me not to talk to you about it just, you know...
Tim vroeg me om er niet met je over te praten, zodat je het weet...
But I just wanted you and I to look at each other and be on the same page now.
Maar ik wilde dat jij en ik naar elkaar kijken en nu op dezelfde pagina zijn.
I don't really think that you're mind is into it.
Ik denk echt niet dat je geest erin is.
I don't know if you feel like you're letting me down
Ik weet niet of je voelt alsof je me teleurstelt
because you're really not. So I need you to hear you say it,
want dat is niet zo. Dus moet ik je het horen zeggen
"I'm not fighting." - That's really hard.
"Ik ga niet vechten." - Dat is echt moeilijk.
- But you gotta say it because I don't want there be any--just tell me
- Maar je moet het zeggen omdat ik niet wil dat er een--maar vertel me
you're not fighting and then we'll get over it. See what I'm saying?
dat je niet gaat vechten en dan komen we er wel overheen. Zie je wat ik bedoel?
- Uh-huh. Give me--give me a day. Can I have a day?
-Uh-huh. Geef me--geef me een dag. Kan ik een dag hebben?
Or can I have this evening, the rest of this evening?
Of kan ik deze avond, de rest van deze avond hebben?
- Yeah, you can have the rest of this evening.
-Ja, je hebt de rest van deze avond.
And there's no sweat off on nobody's back. Start fresh.
En er is geen zweet op niemand's rug. Frisse start.
- *[Tim] We're gonna do little gloves today and Wednesday, okay?*
- [Tim] We gaan kleine handschoenen vandaag en woensdag doen, ok?
Just so we kinda take some of the heat off you guys
Gewoon zodat we een beetje van de heette van jullie afnemen
not beating each other up so bad, you know?
elkaar niet zo slecht te slaan, weet je?
[timer rings]
[timer rinkelt]
[thud, thud, thud]
[plof, plof, plof]
-*[male voice] Just grab one, June. Just grab one of his legs. Suck it up.**
- [mannelijke stem] Neem er een,June. Pak een van zijn benen. Suck it up.
Little lighter Fakroe. You gotta fight in two weeks.
Kleine lichtere Fakroe. Je moet binnen twee weken vechten.
Lighter. Slow down.
Lichter. Rustig aan.
Oh, Fakroe! Slow down! Go!
Oh, Fakroe! Rustig aan! Go!
Shit! Control yourself. Fucking think this is?
Shit! Hou jezelf onder controle. Wat denk je dat dit is?
[thud, thud, thud]
[plof, plof, plof]
[alarm beeps]
[alarm biept]
Great job! good work. We're there!
Goed gedaan! Goed werk. We zijn er!
Just stick around.
Blijf gewoon rondhangen.
Alby go with D. Let's go repair, you got 30 seconds.
Alby ga met D. Laten we gaan herstellen, je hebt 30 seconden.
[thud, thud, thud]
[plof, plof, plof]
Get down!
Ga neer!
-*[Tim] Bring him down.*
- [Tim] Breng hem neer.
[heavy breathing]
[zware ademhaling]
[thud]
[plof]
-*[male] You gotta have to pay for it one way or another, might as well do it now.*
-  [man] Je zult er moeten voor betalen op één of andere manier, kan evengoed nu.
-*[male] Take it like a man, come on!*
- [man] Neem het als een man, komaan!
-*[male] Keep your hands up, Albert. Come back to your face. *
- [man] Houd je handen omhoog, Albert. Kom terug naar je gezicht.
[heavy breathing]
[zware ademhaling]
[beep]
[biep]
♪ [music] ♪
♪ [muziek] ♪
- I'm thankful you know, for the ass beating I just received.
-Ik ben dankbaar weet je, voor de pak slaag die ik net ontvangen heb.
You know these guys are just trying to keep real with me.
Weet je deze jongens proberen zich gewoon echt met mij te houden.
They're just trying to show like, "*Hey, you need to be in the gym."*
Ze proberen gewoon te laten zien zoals, " Hey, jij moet in de gym zijn."
You know after two rounds of sitting there and dying when--
Je weet na twee rondes van hier te zitten sterven dat--
You know, like Tim said, two months ago
Weet je, zoals Tim al zei, twee maanden geleden
I was killing almost everybody, you know.
Ik wasbijna iedereen aan het verslaan, weet je.
So, this isn't the last opportunity I'll have.
Dus, dit is niet de laatste kans die ik zal krijgen.
And I--I really need to be thankful for that.
En ik--ik moet daar echt dankbaar voor zijn.
It's just, it sucks knowing that I let something like this go by.
Het is gewoon, het is klote te weten dat ik zoiets als dit voorbij liet gaan.
You know, it might be small, might be big, but it was there.
Misschien wel klein, misschien wel groot, maar het was er.
And I'm not one to--to like it when I screw up.
En ik ben niet iemand om--om het leuk te vinden wanneer ik het verziek.
- *[Tim] In fighting, most of the time, you're, you're own worst enemy.*
- [Tim] In vechten, de meestal, ben je, je eigen ergste enemy.
*You know unfortunately, Albert beat himself.*
Weet je jammer genoeg, Albert versloeg zichzelf.
♪ [music] ♪
♪ [muziek] ♪
*You know fighting is a microcosm for life.*
Weet je vechten is een microkosmos voor leven.
*The credit belongs to the person that's out there.*
Het krediet behoort tot de persoon die daar buiten is.
*And the person that's putting themselves on the line*
En de persoon die zichzelf op de lijn zet
*to do something, to be something. *
om iets te doen, iets te zijn.
*To push their level and push who they are as a person*
Om hun niveau te duwen en te duwen op wie ze als een persoon zijn
* to greater and greater heights.*
naar steeds grotere hoogten.
[tap, tap, tap]
[tik, tik, tik]
- *[Tim] For Dustin Poirier to lose,*
- [Tim] Voor Dustin Poirier te verliezen,
*It's gonna take someone to beat him but Dustin is not gonna beat himself.*
Iemand zal hem moeten verslaan, maar Dustin plant niet zichzelf te verslaan.
[thump]
[stomp]
[thud, thud, thud]
[plof, plof, plof]
-*[male] Come on reach it*
- [man] Kom op bereik het
- *[male voice] As you jab, that's a measuring stick.*
- [mannelijke stem] Als je steekt, dat is een meetstok.
-*[Dustin] Reach you literally across--*
- [Dustin] Bereik je letterlijk over--
-*[male voice] Well, yeah, but your jab is like a measuring stick.*
- [mannelijke stem] Nou, ja, maar je steek is als een meetstok.
*That's what put you in position. That's where I'm gonna be, right there.*
Dat is wat u in positie zet. Dat is waar ik ga zijn, juist daar.
-*[male voice] Everyone can walk, but then to be a run way model,*
- [mannelijke stem] Iedereen kan lopen, maar om dan een baanmodel te worden,
*you have to learn how to walk.*
moet je leren om te wandelen.
*He knows how to fight. *
Hij weet hoe te te vechten.
*But he just possess an unbelievable amount of heart and determination.*
Maar hij bezit slechts een ongelooflijke hoeveelheid hart en vastberadenheid.
*And if you can give a fighter a heart and determination, *
En als je een vechter een hart en vastberadenheid kunt geven,
*the sky's absolutely the limit. *
the hemel is absoluut de limiet.
*'Cause this ultimately--*
Want dit uiteindelijk--
*the MMA and the boxing's gonna end one day and they didn't learn anything*
de MMA en het boksen gaat op een dag eindigen en ze leerden niets
* while they were boxing, then this was all done in vain.*
terwijl ze aan het boksen waren,dan was dit allemaal voor niets gedaan.
[thud, thud, thud]
[plof, plof, plof]
-What make you hit those angles, you know?
- Wat maakt je die hoeken raken, weet je?
- *[Gil] You're looking at that hook before you throw it.*
- [Gil] Je kijkt naar die haak voordat je die gooit.
*I saw you doing it. You were doing this, *bam, bam*. *
Ik zag het je doen. Je bam bam deed dit, .
*And you look at that hook before you threw it.*
En je kijkt naar die haak voordat je die wierp.
- 'Cause I'm trying to keep my hook like--
-Want ik probeer mijn haak te houden zoals--
even with my head I'm trying not to arm it like I used to.
zelfs met mijn hoofd probeer ik niet om het te bewapenen zoals ik gewend ben.
I used to throw hooks from here.
Vroeger gooide ik haken van hier.
-That's good. That's your hook.
-Dat is goed. Dat is uw haak.
- I'm thinking about it a little bit too much.
- Ik denk er een beetje te veel aan.
- You look good, you look good.
- Het zit goed, het zit goed.
It's a good thing. A good thing that happen would be for the promotion
Het is iets goed. Iets goeds dat gebeurt is voor de promotie,
would be, if you'd lost.
indien je verloor.
-*[Gil] 'Cause if you lost then I could sell a rematch. *
-[Gil] 'Want als je verloor dan kon ik een rematch verkopen.
If you win I can't sell a rematch. You know?
Als je wint kan ik geen rematch verkopen, weet je?
So, you want to make some real money. You'd get ready to lose.
Dus, als je wat echt geld wilt verdienen, maak je jezelf klaar om te verliezen.
- Shit! Everybody got their dreams.
- Shit! Iedereen heeft zijn dromen.
No rematching buddy.
Geen rematching maatje.
♪ [music] ♪
♪ [muziek] ♪
- *[Gil] The family element is essential to us because USA-MMA is my family.*
-  [Gil] Het familie element is vitaal voor ons omdat USA-MMA mijn familie is.
*Me, my wife, my children and we all promote this event.*
Ik, mijn vrouw, mijn kinderen en we bevorden dit evenement allemaal.
*But when we're all together out there trying to enjoy a good day together.*
Maar wanneer we allemaal samen zijn en samen van een goede dag proberen
*And we're promoting the event *
Te genieten en we bevorderen dit evenement
*at the same time and people see me and and my wife,*
op hetzelfde moment en mensen zien mij en mijn vrouw,
*my son, my daughter who is 3 years old passing, off flyers,*
mijn zoon, mijn dochter die 3 jaar oud is, delen flyers uit,
*it's not a gimmick, but it helps. *
het is geen trucje, maar het helpt wel.
*It helps people see that, *"Man! this is alright,"* you know?*
Het helpt mensen zien dat, 'Man! Dit is ok,'  weet je?
*"It could be okay. Lets go, lets give it a shot."*
"Het kan wel goed zijn. Laten we gaan, laten we het eens proberen."
[drum beating]
[drum slaat]
- That's a big face.
- Dat is een groot gezicht.
-You see the face over there? Say, "Throw me something, mister"
- Zie je dat gezicht daar? Zeg, "Gooi me iets, meneer."
-*[girl] Throw me something, mister.*
- [girl] Gooien me iets, meneer.
That's a good stuff, the coins. Look. You got coins? Look, grab your coins.
Dat is een goed spul, de munten. Kijk. Heb je munten? Kijk, pak uw munten.
Come on ya'all
Kom op iedereen
-* [Gil] How long before we have to--*
- [Gil] Hoe lang voordat we moeten--
- Oh you got, you got a couple of minutes.
-Oh je hebt, je hebt een paar minuten.
- I gotta wake my wife up, take the kids to school.
-Ik moet mijn vrouw wakker maken , de kinderen naar school brengen.
- We'll talk the aspect-- - Hey!
-We zullen het apect bespreken--- Hey!
-*[wife] Hi!*
- [vrouw] Hallo!
- Okay, just making sure, I'm about to go on camera--
-Ok, gewoon om er zeker over te zijn, ik ga bijna op camera--
- Tell us how good we look, tell us if we look good.
-Vertel ons hoe goed we lijken, vertel ons als we er goed uitzien.
- Bob said to tell him if he looks good. Bye!
- Bob zei om hem te vertellen als hij ziet er goed uitziet. Tot ziens!
Alright bye!
Ok, tot ziens!
- Alright, that was a look at Fitness first,
- Ok, dat was een kijkje op Fitness eerst,
23 minutes after 6 o'clock, Wednesday morning
23 minuten na 6 uur, woensdag ochtend
on Fox 2. Gill Guillory with USA-MMA.
op Fox 2. Gill Guillory met USA-MMA.
We are taking it up a notch this coming Saturday at the Cajundome.
Wij nemen het een betje omhoog deze komende zaterdag in de Cajundome.
- That's right - Who are we gonna see in action?
-Dat isjuist - Wie krijgen we in actie te zien?
- Well, we're gonna see in the main event,
- Wel, we gaan in het hoofdevenement zien,
Derrick Krantz from Texas versus Dustin Poirier out of St. Martinville.
Derrick Krantz uit Texas versus Dustin Poirier uit St. Martinville.
That's for our USA-MMA championship.
Dat is voor ons USA-MMA kampioenschap.
Paul Swallow from Lake Charles will be in, he'll be fighting also.
Paul Swallow van Lake Charles zal er zijn, hij gaat ook vechten.
We have a ton of Gladiator guys that'll be fighting in the show.
We hebben een ton van Gladiator jongens die in de show zullen vechten.
Cajun karate guys fighting on the show.
Cajun karate jongens vechten op de show.
We have people from Oklahoma,Dallas.
We hebben mensen van Oklahoma, Dallas.
-* [Bob] All right, also, I'm gonna be the ring announcer.*
- [Bob] Ok, ook, ik ga de ring omroeper zijn.
So mark that done, you know what date.
Dus merk dat gedaan, je weet welke datum.
And of course, the all important, there's gonna be ring girls.
En natuurlijk het aller belangrijkste, er zullen ringmeisjes zijn.
- We got ring girls but we have a special announcement today.
- We hebben ring meisjes, maar we hebben een speciale aankondiging vandaag.
Our special guest ring girl will be Ms. Julie Darcy.
Ons special guest ring meisje zal Miss Julie Darcy zijn.
- [Bob] No. You don't wanna do that.
-[Bob] Nee. Je wilt dat niet doen.
- *[Gil] I'm still nervous, I mean, you know,*
- [Gil]Iik ben nog steeds nerveus, ik bedoel, je weet wel,
A show that cost you a $55,000, if I lose $55,000 I gotta go to work,
Een show die je $55.000 kost als ik $55.000 verlies moet ik gaan werken,
you know, I mean...
weet je, ik bedoel
I'm not rich. I mean I work but I work for myself.
Ik ben niet rijk. Ik bedoel ik werk maar ik werk voor mezelf.
- *[Bob] Fifty-five thousand!*
- [Bob] Vijfenvijftig duizend!
- That's what it cost to put on a show, you know.
-Dat is wat het kost om een show op te zetten, weet je.
- [Bob] People have come to realize now that there's so much...
-[Bob] Mensen beseffen nu dat er zoveel...
- [Gil] Right - You get what you paid for.
- [Gil] Juist - Je krijgt wat je voor betaald.
-[Tim] It's tough to make a living fighting. It's really tough.
- [Tim] Het is lastig om je boterham al vechtend te verdienen. Het is echt lastig.
Your entire career is controlled with your hands.
Je hele carrière wordt gecontroleerd met je handen.
*You build your own destiny,*
Je bouwt je eigen lot,
*brick by brick, with you own hands. Fight by fight.*
steen voor steen, met je eigen handen. Vechtpartij na vechtpartij.
I don't see martial arts as a career path. I see it as a lifestyle.
Vechtsport zie ik niet als een carrière. Ik zie het als een levensstijl.
*I enjoy the fear, I enjoy the nervousness, I enjoy that.*
Ik geniet van de angst, ik geniet van de nervositeit, ik geniet daarvan.
That's why I do this
Dat is waarom ik dit doe.
The point of the entire thing is to build yourself into a better person.
Het punt van het hele ding is om jezelf tot een betere persoon om te bouwen.
Not to make yourself a richer person.
Niet om jezelf een rijker persoon te maken.
- [Dustin] I mean, I feel a lot of pressure with this fight.
-[Dustin] Ik bedoel, ik voel heel wat druk met deze vechtpartij.
Because I just signed that contract with Dinero Sports Marketing.
Omdat ik heb net dat contract tekende met Dinero Sport Marketing.
What is he gonna think if I'd lose this fight?
Wat gaat hij denken als ik dit gevecht verlies?
That's putting pressure on me thinking about that. That's why, if I lose this fight,
Dat zet druk op mij daarover te denken. Dat is waarom, als ik dit gevecht verlies,
is my manager gonna say,
mijn manager zal zeggen,
"Well, I think he's even ready to fight even tougher guys now."
"Nou, ik denk dat hij zelfs bereid is om nu nog moeilijkere kerels te vechten."
When it come down to it. All I can do is fight
Wanneer het er op neer komt. Alles wat ik kan doen is vechten.
[thud, thud, thud]
[plof, plof, plof]
- [male] Give me some more, Give me some more
- [man] Geef me wat meer, geef me wat meer.
- [Dustin] It's not hard to harm another person.
-[Dustin] Het is niet moeilijk om een andere persoon te kwetsen.
To knock another person out.
Om een ander knock-out te slaan.
I mean this is a simple task that has to be done in the cage.
Ik bedoel dat dit is een eenvoudige taak die moet worden gedaan in de kooi.
And just as simple as I can do it to you, you can do it to me.
En net zo eenvoudig dat ik het aan u kan doen, kunt u het aan mij doen.
- This guys coming to, basically, in Dustin's living room
-Deze jongens komen, in principe, in Dustin's woonkamer
at his home and trying to defeat him.
bij zijn thuis en proberen om hem te verslaan.
This is Dustin's house! This is Lafayette, Louisiana.
Dit is Dustin's huis! Dit is Lafayette, Louisiana.
And it's his home where he was born and raised.
En het is zijn huis waar hij werd geboren en getogen.
This guy can't come to Lafayette and win this fight. It's impossible!
Deze kerel kan niet naar Lafayette komen en dat gevecht winnen, Dat is onmogelijk!
-[Dustin] Anything can happen in fighting.
-[Dustin] Alles kan gebeuren in vechten.
All it takes is one mistake, one punch.
Alles wat er nodig is, is een fout, een pons.
Me knowing that. Makes me a little bit prepared for a good fight I think.
Dat wetende. Maakt me een beetje voorbereid voor een goed gevecht denk ik.
[birds chirping]
[vogels tjilpen]
*I want this fight more than anything and I think about it 24 hours a day*
Ik wil dit gevecht meer dan om het even wat, ik denk er 24 uur per dag over na.
Derrick's fighting the best Dustin Poirier anybody has ever fought
Derrick zal de beste Dustin Poirier vechten die iemand ooit heeft gevochten.
One sixty one on the money.
Één eenenzestig op het geld.
Six more pounds.
Nog 3 kg.
*Fourteen pounds already*
Al zes kg.
Today's Thursday, four days, 14 pounds. You know I'm eating three times a day now.
Vandaag donderdag, vier dagen, 6 kg. Weet je ik eet nu drie keer per dag.
While I'm cutting weight, only six to eight ounce piece of fish.
Terwijl ik gewicht verlies, slechts een 170 tot 230 gram stukje vis.
But still you know, put the little bit of sides but still that's way better, you know,
Maar toch weet je, zet de kleine beetjes maar dat is nog altijd beter, weet je,
keep my body from breaking itself down.
Houd mijn lichaam van zichzelf af te breken.
Oh, man! Raw organic coconut butter. It's so horrible
Oh, man! Rauwe biologische kokosnoot boter. Dat is dus verschrikkelijk
I'm suppose to be takin these because I'm not eating any carbohydrates really.
Ik moet normaal deze innemen omdat ik niet echt koolhydraten eet.
Beside the Quiona, but that's not too many.
Naast de Quiona, maar dat is niet veel.
And your body needs energy so it doesn't break down the muscles.
En uw lichaam heeft energie nodig zodat het de spieren niet breekt.
[crackling]
[kraken]
When I cut weight, I'd like to watch the food network.
Wanneer ik gewicht verlies, kijk ik graag naar the food network.
Pretending I'm swimming in a pool of icing like that.
Doen alsof ik aan het zwemmen ben in een zwembad met glazuur of zo.
-*[mans voice] What else sounds good?*
- [man's stem] Wat anders klinkt goed?
How much time you got?
Hoeveel tijd heb je?
I love ice cream. Like the cookies. Like ice cream sandwiches. What!
Ik hou van ijs. Hou van koekjes. Hou van ijs broodjes. Wat!
The make peanut butter one inside Wal-mart, between two chocolate things
Ze maken er zo van die pindakaas in Wal-Mart, tussen twee chocolade dingetjes
The peanu-- the ice cream is peanut butter flavored.
De pinda--het ijs is pindakaas smaak.
I'd eat a whole box of 'em after I fight.
Ik zou een hele doos ervan eten nadat ik gevochten heb.
[men chattering]
[mannen babbelen]
- Hello, this is Gil. We have a ton of tickets, man.
- Hallo, dit is Gil. We hebben een ton van tickets, man.
Grab about 50 of your friends and come on down
Pak ongeveer 50 van je vrienden en kom af.
If we don't sell tickets. This house's is on the line.
Als we geen tickets verkopen. Dit huis staat op de lijn.
*For us to be profitable, we have to do everything.*
Voor ons winstgevend te zijn, moeten we alles doen.
*We have to do the lighting, ticket taking, ticket selling.*
We moeten de verlichting doen, nemen van ticket, ticket verkoop.
*We have to do everything or we loose everything.*
We moeten alles doen of we verliezen alles.
- Whatever I'm wearing to fight. I have to put it inside a target bag.
-Wat ik draag om te vechten, moet ik in een doelzak doen.
Has to be target bag.
Het moet een doelzak zijn.
I have to buy juicy fruity bubble gum and chew it the whole day before I fight.
Ikmoet sappige fruitige kauwgomkopen om de hele dag te kauwen voordat ik vecht.
I'd be fighting Derrick Krantz, my breath would be smelling like bubble gum
Ik zou dan Derrick Krantz vechten, mijn adem ruikt dan net zoals bubble gum
Mango flavored Walgreen's Pedialyte every time.
Mango smaak Walgreen's Pedialyte elke keer.
Not Pedialyte brand, Walgreen's brand. It taste like victory.
Niet Pedialyte merk, Walgreen van merk. Smaakt net zoals overwinning.
For the weigh-ins, I always have to buy new boxers
Voor het inwegen, moet ik altijd nieuwe boxers kopen,
I think I'm on a roll with weighing in with a gray one's on.
Ik denk dat ik op een rol ben met inwegen met een grijze aan.
So I think I'd probably wear these cause these are kinda cool
Dus ik denk dat ik waarschijnlijk deze ga dragen want ze zijn cool.
They have a black top and they're gray, so it's pretty cool.
Ze hebben een zwarte top en ze zijn grijs, dus het is redelijk cool.
I think I'll weigh-in with these on most likely.
Ik denk dat ikzeer waarschijnlijk ga inwegen met deze aan.
Unless somethin' changes in my mind, I'd have to wear these.
Tenzij iets mijn gedachten verandert, zou ik deze moeten dragen.
We'll see. Otherwise I'm normal.
We zullen zien. Anders ben ik normaal.
[tv playing]
[tv speelt]
- [Jere Folley Chaissou] It's a hard week for all of us,
-[Jere Folley Chaissou] Het is een harde week voor ons allen,
It's like, a year ago, yesterday, my mom died.
Het is een jaar geleden, gisteren dat mijn moeder stierf.
And I know that, that's been heavy on him very heavy. Very heavy.
En ik weet dat dat zwaar op hem is geweest, zeer zwaar. Zeer zwaar.
Because she and I raised him by the skin of our teeth.
Omdat zij en ik hem met de huid van onze tanden grootgebracht hebben.
When he points up to heaven after he wins, he's pointing up to his grandma.
Als hij naar de hemel wijst na hij wint, wijst hij omhoog naar zijn grootmoeder.
She's got the best seat in the house
Ze heeft de beste zitplaats in het huis
♪ [music] ♪
♪ [muziek] ♪
- [Gil] Come a long way since the rodea arena's but,
-[Gil] Ben een lang weg gegaan zinds de rodea arena's maar,
we may go back to the rodeo arena.
We gaan misschien terugkeren naar de rodeo arena.
The profit margin is so high on the rodeo arena, that--
De winstmarge op de rodeo-arena, is zo hoog dat--
that's what justifies going there in the first place.
dat is wat rechtvaardigt er in de eerste plaats te gaan.
So, if we get 5,000 people tomorrow night,
Dus, als we 5.000 mensen morgenavond krijgen
We'll be back. It just depends man, I'm scared.
Komen we terug. Het hangt er gewoon van af man, ik ben bang.
Scared to death.
Doodsbang.
It's a big step you know.
Het is een grote stap weet je wel.
-*[announcer] One fifty-five is the weight class. Derrick Krantz willl be up first.*
- [omroeper] Een vijfenvijftig is de gewichtsklasse.Derrick Krantz gaat eerst.
*One fifty-five point four.*
Een vijfenvijftig punt vier.
*Dustin Poirier, one fifty-five point four.*
Dustin Poirier, één vijfenvijftig punt vier.
[audience clapping]
[publiek klapt]
*One, two, three, four. One, two, three, four.*
Een, twee, drie, vier.
*One, two, one, two, one, two.*
Een, twee, een, twee, een, two.
*Let's - we may have to make some minor adjustments once again.*
Laten we - we gaan waarschijnlijk wat kleine veranderingen moeten maken.
-*[male] When was the last time you passed out?*
- [mann] Wanneer was de laatste keer dat je flauwviel?
When was the last time you fought?
Wanneer was de laatste keer dat je gevochten hebt?
- This is your first fight? Never fought anywhere in Texas at all?
-Dit is uw eerste gevecht? Nog nooit ergens in Texas gevochten?
-* [Gil] This is my man.*
- [Gil] Dit is mijn man.
*Derrick D-Rock Krantz, here for the USA-MMA 155 pound title.*
Derrick  D-Rock  Krantz, hier voor de USA-MMA 70 kg titel.
Mr. Krantz, What is your projection for the main event this evening?
Mr. Krantz, wat is uw projectie voor het hoofdevenement vanavond?
- I'll take a first round knock out any day.
-Ik neem een eerste ronde knock out elke dag.
- And become the USA-MMA 155 pound champion
- En de USA-MMA 70 kg kampioen worden
and hopefully move on to bigger and better things
en hopelijk naar grotere en betere dingen doorstoten
Here and the near future.
Hier en de nabije toekomst.
Derrick D. Krantz and Gil "The Thrill" Guillory checking out.
Derrick D. Krantz en Gil "The Thrill" Guillory checken uit.
- We want everyone here from Lafayette Louisiana.
-We willen iedereen hier uit Lafayette, Louisiana.
It's the USA-MMA champion on the line.
Het is de USA-MMA kampioen op de lijn.
Derrick Krantz will be going up against Dustin Poirier, Poirier
Derrick Krantz zal tegen Dustin Poirier gaan.
♪ [music] ♪
♪ [muziek] ♪
- We welcome you here to Cajun country.
-Wij heten u welkom hier bij Cajun land.
[foreign language]
[vreemde taal]
[crowd cheering]
[menigte juicht]
- I'm proud of you, good work. Thank you, man.
-Ik ben trots op je, goed werk. Dank u, man.
- Thank you, thank you very much. I can't breathe but it's all good.
-Dank u, hartelijk dank. Ik kan niet ademen, maar het is allemaal goed.
Hey Bau. Hey Bau, are you okay?
Hey Bau. Hey Bau, ben je ok?
- *[Bau] What? Just a broken nose.*
- [Bau] Wat? Gewoon een gebroken neus.
- [Gil] Bau's got a broken nose and swellling.
-[Gil] Bau heeft een gebroken neus en zwelling..
He got into war with a 260 pound guy and -- I mean...
Hijwas in een oorlog met een 118 kg wegende kerel en -- ik bedoel...
He says his head hurt and they're trying to take him away in
Hij zegt dat zijn hoofd pijn en ze proberen hem mee te nemen in
an ambulance for a broken nose.
een ambulance voor een gebroken neus.
I'm like, "Dude, you're not going away in an ambulance.
Ik ben zo van, "Kerel, je gaat niet weg in een ambulance.
Have your momma drive you to the hospital," you know.
Laat je moeder je naar het ziekenhuis voeren," weet je wel.
It's like crazy. He'll be fine, it's just they'r scared you know.
Het is gek. Hij zal wel ok zijn, het is gewoon dat ze bang zijn weet je.
They don't understand. They're scared.
Ze begrijpen niet. Ze zijn bang.
He's never been beat like that. He's a fighter though.
Hij heeft nooit geweest zo geslagen geweest. Hij is wel een vechter.
He's fuckin' as tough as nails and he did what he could.
Hij is verdomme zo taai als nagels en hij deed wat hij kon.
Baby girl, love of my life.
Kleine meid, liefde van mijn leven.
Come with daddy. wanna come with daddy. I love you,
Kom met papa. Wil je met papa meekomen. Ik zie je graag.
wanna come work with me? Let's go work
Wil je met me komen werken? Laten we gaan werken.
[hard breathing]
[harde ademhaling]
- Dustin Poirier will hit Derrick Krantz so hard,
- Dustin Poirier zal Derrick Krantz zo hard raken
the alarm in the nearby bank will go off.
het alarm in de nabijgelegen bank zal afgaan.
- *[Dustin] What you think?, It's perfect.* - [Tim] You're gonna need it.
- [Dustin] Wat denk je? Het is perfect.- [Tim] Je zult het nodig hebben.
[announcer calling]
[omroeper roept]
- [Dustin] It's about to go down. - [Tim] I know.
-[Dustin] Het gaat bijna neer. -[Tim] Ik weet het.
- *[Gil] Many fans and family and friends do not understand the reality of fighting.*
- [Gil] veel fans en familie en vrienden begrijpen de realiteit van vechten niet.
- [announcer] Derrick D-rock.
-[omroeper] Derrick D-rock.
*They immediately pawn off Dustin's opponent.*
Ze pionnen onmiddellijk Dustin's tegenstander uit.
*As if he's some person on a prison release program,*
Alsof hij een persoon op een gevangenis-programma is,
*just coming here to get beat up.*
gewoon naar hier gekomen hier om geslagen te worden.
*And get some cigarettes or something. *
En sommige sigaretten of iets te krijgen.
*This is another dangerous trained professional fighter,*
Dit is een andere gevaarlijke opgeleide professionele vechter,
*who has finished a lot of individuals. *
die klaar is met een heleboel individuen.
*And he's coming here to destroy Dustin.*
En hij komt hier om Dustin te vernietigen.
♪ [music] ♪
♪ [muziek] ♪
[crowd yelling and cheering]
[menigte schreeuwt en juicht]
- *[male] Let's work baby, hand's up chin down.*
- [Gil] Laten we werken baby, handen op kin naar beneden.
[slamming on the floor]
[slaan op de vloer]
[crowd cheering]
[menigte juicht]
*[male] Use a clock face, use a clock face.*
[man] Gebruik een wijzerplaat, gebruik een wijzerplaat.
*[man] Keep working it, keep working it*
[man] Blijf het bewerken, blijf het bewerken.
-* [male] Lock it up, lock it up, grab your shit, keep the triangle.*
- [man] Sluit het op, sluit het op, grijp je shit, houd de driehoek.
- *[male] Lock your right foot down. Lock your triangle and pull his hand.*
-[man] Vergrendel je rechtervoet. Vergrendel je driehoek en trek zijn hand.
*[male] Grab the wrist. One more.*
[man] Grijp de pols. Nog een.
- *[male] You your shit Dustin!*
- [man] Gebruik je shit Dustin!
- *[male] Close your guard, tighten it up.* - $$[Derrick] You are doing good.
- [man] Sluit uw hoede, scherp het aan. -[Derrick] Je doet goed.
- $$*[Dustin] Thank you.*
- [Dustin] Dank je.
-* [male] Keep working, control the wrist.*
-[man's stem] Blijf werken, controleer de pols.
*Control the wrist,control the wrist*
Controleer de pols, controleer de pols.
- *[male] Off the bottom Dustin push your hips.*
- [man] Van beneden Dustin duw je heupen.
[horn blowing]
[hoorn blaast]
- Stuck up, don't make me snap. You get out there and fight!
- Zwijg, laat me niet snappen. Je gaat daar en vecht!
Put your chin on and go to work on this boy.
Zet je kin en ga aan deze jongen werken.
This boy does not want to be in the ring with you.
Deze jongen wil niet met je in de ring zijn.
You hear what I'm telling you. You go to work!
Hoor je wat ik zeg. Ga werken!
- [Tim] He's taking you down for a reason.
-[Tim] Hij neemt je neer voor een reden.
You put it in your mind you gonna knock this mother fucker out.
Zet het in uw gedachten dat je deze motherfucker knock-out slaat.
You put your chin on, you put your hands up. You start throwing shots!
Je zet je kin, brengt je handen naar omhoog. Je begint shots te gooien!
Make him punish this thing!
Laat hem dat ding straffen!
- *[male] Hand's up, chin down, bite down, bite them mouth piece, go to work.*
- Handen omhoog, kin naar beneden, neer bijten, bijt je mondstuk, ga werken.
-*[male] Alright take him down.*
-[man] Ok neem hem neer.
- [Tim] It just sometimes it feels like
-[Tim] Het is gewoon soms voelt het alsof
my hearts gonna come out of my chest you know.
mijn hart uit mijnborst zal vallen weet je.
♪ [music] ♪
♪ [muziek] ♪
[crowd cheering]
[menigte juicht]
[Tim] Work it now, work it, work it.
[Tim] Bewerk het nu, werk het, werk het.
♪ [music] ♪
♪ [muziek] ♪
- [Tim] Proud of you. You beat that thing.
-[Tim] Trots op je. Je versloeg dat ding.
You deserve it.
-[Dustin] Je verdient het.
- [Tim] I know I don't say it, but I love these guys.
-[Tim]Iik weet dat ik het niet zeg maar ik hou van deze kerels.
*[announcer] How about a round of applause for both fighters.*
[omroeper] Laten we een ronde van applaus voor beide vechters.
Wow!
Wauw!
[crowd cheering]
[menigte juicht]
*Fighters to the center of the ring. *
Vechters naar het midden van de ring.
*Dustin Poirier!*
Dustin Poirier!
[crowd cheering]
[menigte juicht]
♪ [music] ♪
♪ [muziek] ♪
- [Dustin] People will say this is a crazy dream
-[Dustin] Mensen zullen zeggen dat dit een gekke droom is
or like a fantasy dream that I'm chasing.
of als een fantasie droom waar ik achter ga.
And I won't be able to do it, you know, what's their dream?
en ik niet zal kunnen om het te doen. Weet je, wat is hun droom?
What are they gonna do with their life?
Wat zijn ze gaan doen met hun leven?
- *[Gil] I wish that when I was his age*.
- [Gil] Ik wil dat toen ik . zijn leeftijd was
* I had the ability to separate those things*
Ik had de mogelijkheid om die dingen van elkaar te verwijderen
*and get those bad things out of my life. *
en krijg die slechte dingen uit mijn leven.
*I didn't care man. I did--I partied and tried to burn the candle at both ends. *
Het kon me niet schelen. Ik feestte en trachtte de kaars aan beide kanten
He's not doing that.
te branden. Hij gaat dat niet doen.
When I look at Dustin, I look at
Als ik kijk naar Dustin, kijk ik naar
- and of course dangerous word again "potential".
- en uiteraard gevaarlijke wordt opnieuw " potentieel ".
Potential to actually be something in this sport.
Potentieel om daadwerkelijk iets in deze sport te zijn
Twenty one with his mind on the game.
Eenentwintig met zijn geest op het spel.
- *[Dustin] "Fortune favors are bold," you know, Virgil said that.*
- [Dustin] "Fortuin gunsten, worden vet," weet je, dat Virgil zei dat
- So a kid that's 21 years old with 15 fights and one loss.
-[Tim] Dus een kind dat 21 jaar oud is met 15 gevechten en 1 verlies.
Would for sure need to step out a little bit
Zou zek een klein beetje moeten uitstappen
and go fight in the major league organization
en ga vechten in de major league-organisatie.
[crowd roaring]
[menigte brult]
- [male] Three combo, hus, hus, hus! Good. One combo.
- [man] Drie combo, hus, hus, hus! Goed. Een combo.
- [Dustin] Hus, hus, hus. hus!
-[Dustin] hus, hus, hus. Hus
♪ [music] ♪ [
♪ [muziek] ♪
- [Dustin] It's for me and my wife and family.
-[Dustin] het is voor mij en mijn vrouw en familie
- [Gil] Somebody's dreams gonna get crushed tonight.
-[Gil] iemands dromen gaan vanavond verpletterd worden.
And we're fairly certain it's gonna be Derek Gauthier's dream.
En we zijn vrij zeker dat het Derek Gauthier's droom zal zijn.
*We're not here to crush Derrick or hurt Derrick*
Wij zijn hier niet om Derrick te verpletteren of Derrick te kwetsen
*but we are here to put a yield sign in his dreams.*
maar we zijn hier om een teken van de opbrengst in zijn dromen
-*[Tim] Just like we always say*.
- [Tim] Net als wij altijd zeggen .
*You could walk to the ring with a 100 chicks*
Je zou kunnen lopen naar de ring met een 100 kuikens
and have any nickname you want
en elk bijnaam die u wilt hebben
*But once the door closes down. Ain't nobody coming to save you.*
Maar zodra de deur gesloten is, komt niemand om je te redden.
*Nobody saves you. *
Niemand bespaart je.
You got stitches, stitches? you get stitches? No? Let me see.
Heb je stikken, stikken? Kreeg je stikken? Nee? Even kijken.
-* [Gil] It's important for a fighter mentally and spiritually ,*
- [Gil] Het is belangrijk voor een vechter, mentaal en spiritueel
to be able to walk into an enemy territory
Om te kunnen lopen in een vijandelijk gebied
and walk into a place where the cards are stacked against you.
en lopen in een plaats waar de kaarten zijn gestapeld tegen u.
And the crowd is cheering for the other opponent
En de menigte juicht voor de andere tegenstander
and you were brought in to be beaten.
en jij werdt ingevoerd om verslagen te worden.
You were brought in to be championed against.
Je werdt ingevoerd om gekampioend tegen te worden.
I've done this walk a couple of times and it changed me as a fighter.
Ik heb deze wandeling een paar keer gedaan en het veranderde me als vechter.
[crowd cheering]
[menighte juicht]
- This is your destiny. Fuck this mother fucker's world up.
- Dit is je lot. Fuck die motherfucker zijn wereld.
Let's go Dustin, let's get to business.
Laten we gaan Dustin, laten we zaken doen.
[crowd howling and whistling]
[menigte brult en fluit]
[referee]Watch the take down. hands up, chin down. Flurries. Fight!
[scheidsrechter] Kijk voor de take down. Handen op, kin beneden. Vlagen. Vecht!
[horn honking]
[hoorn toetert]
- *[Tim] Watch the kicks, watch out lets go! *
- [Tim] Kijk naar de schoppen,kijk uit, ga nu!
*Watch the horn shot coming out. Keep your jab hand up, buddy.*
Kijk de hoorn schot eruit koment. Hou je steekhand op, maatje.
*Good work! Good work! *
Goed werk! Goed werk!
*Perfect, perfect. Protect with that glove. Show him the power*
Perfect, perfect. Die curve beschermen met die handschoen. Toon hem de kracht
*Watch - he's ahead of you. Heads up when you're throwing.*
Kijk - hij is voor je. Hoofd op wanneer je gooit.
*Touch him on the chin*
Raak je kin met je handschoen aan.
[punching] *Go for the throat!*
[ponsen] Ga voor de keel!
[crash on the floor] [crowd cheering]
[stort neer op de vloer] [menigte juicht]
- [Tim] Wazzup my baby, wazzup my baby, wazzup my baby
- [Tim] Wazzup my baby, wazzup my baby, wazzup my baby
- [Albert] I love it.
- [Albert] Ik hou ervan.
♪ [music] ♪
♪ [muziek] ♪
[announcer] *The winner by knock out. Dustin Poirier!*
[omroeper] Gewonnen door knock-out, Dustin Poirier!"
- [Albert] Beautiful!
- [Albert] Mooi zo!
- [Tim] Our main goal is not to win titles,
- [Tim] Onze belangrijkste doel is niet om titels te winnen,
win championships and be the greatest.
om kampioenschappen te winnen en de beste te zijn,
We build better men
Wij bouwen betere mannen.
- *Four, three, two one.*
-Vier, drie, twee, een.
- [Coach] Albert Jordan, Alan Marg... Say it well so I can hear you.
- [Coach] Albert Jordan, Alan Marg... Zeg het goed zodat ik je kan horen.
*Albert Stainback.? * -I shot him.
Albert Stainback.? -Ik schoot hem.
[gong clanging]
[gong klettert]
[crowd clapping]
[menigte klapt]
♪ [music] ♪
♪ [muziek] ♪
- *[announcer] Fighters to the middle of the ring.*
-  [omroeper] Vechters naar. het midden van de ring
- All right let's hear some noise for our fighters.
- Ok laten we wat lawaai voor onze strijders horen.
Lets Make some noise.
Laten we wat lawaai maken.
In the red corner.. Dustin Poirrier, Albert Stainback, "Crazy" Tim Creuder,
In de rode hoek...Dustin Poirier, Albert Stainback, "Crazy" Tim Crader
Gil "The Thrill" Guillory, "Bad" Chad Brousou, Corey Judice.
Gil "The Thrill" Gillorey, "Bad" Chad Brousou, Corey Judice
And in the blue corner. Paul Swallow, Mike "The Truth" Jackson,
En in de blauwe hoek, Paul Swallow, Mike "The Truth" Jackson,
Joe Torres, Ronnie Lis,
Joe Torres, Ronnie List
Derrick "D-Rock" Krantz and Dereck "The Sex Machine" Gauthier.
Derrick "D-Rock" Krantz en Dereck "The Sex Machine" Gauthier.
[foreign language]
Laat de goede tijden rollen.
♪ [music] ♪
♪ [muziek] ♪
And I'm your ring announcer, Bob Moore
En ik ben uw ring omroeper Bob Moore.